<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-chinese-exclusion-act</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85053040/1882-05-13/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Bill+bill+Chinese+signed&st=text&r=0.119,0.563,0.331,0.371,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The Chinese Bill.
The bill signed by the President on the
8th inst., entitled "An act to execute cer
tain treutv stipulations relating to Chinese,"
provides In the first section for the suspen
sion of the immigration of Chinese laborers
to the United States for a period of ten
years, counting from the expiration of
ninety days after the passage of the act,
that is for to years from the 30th dav of
July 1882. The second section provides
lor" tiie punishment of masters of vessels
who shall land in the U. S-, Chinese labor
ers in violation of section first, bv u fine of
$500 for each immigrant and imprisonment
not exceeding one year. Section third pro
vides tor certificates of identity tor Chinese
laborers now in the country, who may
wish to visit China and return. Section
twelve makes it the duty of the President
of tiie United States to cause to be removed
to tiie place from whence they came, and
at the cost of the United States every Chi
nese person who shall have unlawfully en
tered this country by land or water, after
being brought before some justice, judge or
commissioner of a court of tiie United
States. Section thirteen exempts diplo
matic and other officers of tin; Chinese
Government and their body and .musehold
servants from the provisions of the act.
The two following sections are the ones
against which so much opposition lias been
shown by Republican Congressmen.
Section' 14. That hereafter no State
court or court of the United States shall ad
mit Chinese to citizenship; and all laws in
conflict with this act are repealed.
Section- 15. That tiie words "Chinese
Laborei s" wherever used in this act shall
be constructed to mean both skilled and un
skilled laborers and Chinese employ ed in
mining.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
  <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042448/1892-04-30/ed-1/?sp=1&q=act+Act+Chinese+exclusion+Exclusion&st=text&r=-0.267,-0.168,1.466,1.466,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>ONLY ONE MORE RIVER TO CROSS.
Should the Chinese Exclusion Act Only
Expire Tuesday Night.
THE AliCREOATIOS 8PKEA11 ITSELF
A Possible Show for the Agents of the
Government to Get in and do
Likewise.
Detroit, April 29. The woods are
full of-Chinese over in Canada. It is
said tbe denizens of the Flowery King
dom, in large numbers, are' dodging be
hind trees and hiding in sequestered
nooks, ready to make a break for the
United States the minute the clock
strikes 12 on the night of 3d. They
all firmly believe that on May 4th the
Chinese exclusion act will expire, and
they hope to slip into tbe United States
before the law now under consideration,
in congress can be put into effect. This
numerous aggregation has consequently
spread itself out along the border all the
way from here to Vancouver, and is only
biding its time to get into this great
republic. Detroit, however, seems to be
the most favorable point at which the
Celestials can cross the border, for it is
the city most adjacent to Chicago,
whither nearly all of them seem to be
bound. Because of this fact, Detroit has
always been a favorite port at which to
land after the trip through Canada from
the Pacific, and, although there are no
statistic to prove it, it is undisputed
that more Chinese have been smuggled 4
across the Detroit river,, at various
points, than at any other place in the
country. Capt. Pratt, special treasury
agent, says the Chinese are avoiding
Windsor, because they know they will
be closely watched there. The border is
as closely guarded as it can be by the
small force stationed here. There is
more chance of the Chinese trying to
cross Marine city, or the month of the,,
river, than at Detroit.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
  <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83040052/1899-09-08/ed-1/?sp=1&q=coolie+coolies&r=-0.027,0.352,1.145,0.641,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
  <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1901-11-22/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Act+act+Chinese+Exclusion+exclusion&st=text&r=-0.613,-0.296,1.492,1.492,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CHINESE EXCLUSION CONVENTION OPENS
FIGHT IN DEFENSE OF AMERICAN LABOR
PRESIDENT WILL URGE RE-ENACTMENT OF EXCLUSION LAW.
D. C, Nov. 21, 1901. Hon. James D. Phelan, San Francisco, Cal.; I have seen the President. I have the best authority for saying that he will not only recom
mend in his message the re-enactment of the Geary law, but will go further and urge that it be made stronger. J, c. NEEDHAM.
CHINESE QUESTION ONE OF" RACE
TyTy E are the warders of the Golden Gate; we must stand
y y here forever in the pathway of the Orient, and if there
is any danger or trial it is for us to sound the alarm.
I regard the Chinese question as a race question. I regard
it as an international question; and above and over all, a
question involving the preservation of our civilisation. The State
of California, with its sezrn hundred miles of seaboard facing
the Orient, is entitled to speak on this question for tlie people of
the United States. Excerpt from Mayor James D. Phelan' s ad
dress at the Chinese Exclusion Convention.
Leading Citizens Gather to Urge
Re-enactment of the
Geary Law.
IT was a distinctly representative
gathering of business, professional
and laboring men that packed Metro
politan Temple yesterday afternoon
when Mayor Phelan called the Chi
nese Exclusion Convention to order.
Xearly every seat in the large auditorium
•was taken, the lower floor being devoted
to the use of the delegates from all parts
of California, while the gallery was given
up to the general public. All present
seemed to be animated by one impulse,
that of doing their utmost to secure the
re-enactment of the Chinese exclusion act
and thereby prevent the threatened In
vasion of Mongol horclee to the peril and
degradation of American labor.
The gathering was of that character
which lends weight to any public move
ment and the conclusions of which are ac
corded respectful consideration In legisla
tive halls. The convention was not the
outgrowth of political or partisan senti
ment, but of the fear of the people of the
State that the danger which menaces
their advancement and prosperity might,
unless strong measures were taken, be
actually realized. In order that the peo
ple of the East might understand how
the communities on the "Western confines
of the continent feel concerning the un
restricted immigration of Chinese into
their midst, the convention was decided
upon, and it is needless to say that the
memorial which is to be adopted to-day
will prove to be an unanswerable argu
ment to those of the East, who, without
the slightest knowledge of the blight-
Borne characteristics of the Chinese, have
df-clared open sympathy for the coolie
hordes which are only awaiting the ex
piration of the exclusion act in May next
SENATOR PERKINS WOULD CO FURTHER.
/T is our people who pay the taxes that have built up our splendid institutions, and we should
draw the line furtJter, only this is not the time nor occasion. I would permit no one to come into
this country unless he felt as he approaches these shores as Moses did when he approached the
burning bush that he stood upon sacred ground; and the voice coming out of that bush from the
American people is "Unless you love freedom, unless you believe in republican institutions, unless you
believe in the free public schools, you cannot come into this country." Excerpt from Senator Perkins'
address before the Chinese Exclusion Convention.
The San Francisco Call.
In order that they may without molesta
tion invade the United States.
Convention Begins Crusade.
Of the 3000 accredited delegates fr*m all
parts of California fully 2500 were present
at 2:15 o'clock when Mayor Phelan rapped
for order. The hall presented a scene of
animation, which the hearty enthusiasm
of the delegates as well as spectators
served to heighten. The hall was deco
rated with the national colors, while over
the platform was suspended a large sign
bearing the words, "Chinese Exclusion
Convention. For Country, Home and
Civilization." Pinned to the lapels of the
coats of the delegates were badges of
white silk suitably inscribed. Side by side
with the farmer sat representatives of
State, national and county governments,
all animated by the one great desire to
protect American labor against the Orien
tal competition which must inevitably fol
low the refusal of Congress to re-enact
the Chinese exclusion law. On the stage
were Mayor Phelan, Mayor N. P. Snyder
of Los Angeles, Senator George C. Per
kins, Lieutenant Governor Jacob H. Neff,
Congressman Frank Coombs, Rev. Wil
liam Rader, Assistant United States Dis
trict Attorney D. E. McKinlay, ex-Sena
tor A. P. Williams, Congressman S. D.
Woods, A. Sbarboro, president of the
Manufacturers' and Producers' Associa
tion; Supervisors J. P. Booth, L. J.
Dwyer, Samuel Braunhart, Charles Box
ton. Supervisor-Elect William Wynn, H.
A. ilcCraney and others.
The issues of the hour were presented
by Mayor Phelan in a strong opening ad
dress. He was received with warmth and
his allusions to the determined stand
taken by California on the Chinese ques
SAN FRANCISCO, FRIDAY, NOVEMBER 22, 1901.
MAYOR JAMES D. PHELAN ADDRESSING THE DELEGATES TO THE
BIG CHINESE EXCLUSION CONVENTION, WHICH HELD ITS INI
TIAL SESSION YESTERDAY AF TERNOON
The people
of this State, he said, had a right to speak"
for the people of the entire union. He
aroused enthusiasm by a vigorous denial
of the story that the sentiment of the
residents of California concerning Chinese
immigration had changed. Were it pos
sible that advantages might be gained by
the peneral admission of Chinese into the
United States the people of California and
of the Pacific Coast would be the first to
recognize and advocate them. The Mayor
declared that the question was a national
one and that the whole people should rise
up against the danger of a Mongol inva
sion.
Geary Chosen as Chairman.
The convention begin business without
delay after the Mayor had finished his
address. The matter of selecting a
chairman was brought up, and Thomas J.
Geary, author of the Chinese Exclusion
Act, was placed in nomination amid a
considerable display of enthusiams. The
name of Mayor Snyder of Los Angeles
was advanced for tho. honor, but that
gentleman respectfully declined, and took
occasion to second Geary's nomination
Mayor Phelan was also placed in nomina
tion, but declined the honor with thanks
Geary was then chosen by acclamation,
and when he advanced to the platform he
was given a hearty ovation. In his speech
of acceptance he referred to the anti-
Chinese exclusion sentiment prevalent in
the East, and expressed the conviction
that the convention would do much to re
move the erroneous impressions concern
ing the Chinese which had been formed
in the territory east of the Rocky Moun
tains. His reference to the strong atti
tude of President Roosevelt in the mat
ter of the re-enactment was hailed with
wild cheers, and cries of "Good bey.
Teddy!" He held that the advancement
of American comraerco was subsidiary to
the advancement of tne welfare of Am
erican labor. The fundamental princlp'e,
he argued, should be recognized that
without labor there could be no com
merce.dress at the Chinese Exclusion Convention.
Strong Addresses in Behalf of the
Laboring People of the
Coast.
WHEN Mayor Phelan called
the Chinese Exclusion Con
vention to order yesterday
afternoon every seat in the
body of the hall and in the
gallery was occupied by dele
gates and spectators.
After calling the convention to order
Mayor Phelan delivered the following ad
dress:
Personnel of Convention.
Fellow Citizens of the State of California:
It 14 my honor as Mayor of this city, pursuant
to resolution of the Board of Supervisors,
to call this convention to order. It is made up
of our Senators and Representatives in Con
gress, the officials of the State, the counties
and cities of California, of the labor and
trades organizations and of civic society. This
is, in the Judgment of the Board of Supervis
ors, called a representative body, a body
which, when it speaks, will be listened to with
consideration and respect.
The State of California, with its seven hun
dred miles of seaboard fronting tha Pacific,
facing the Orient, is entitled to speak on this
question for the people of the United States.
(Applause.) We may speak, as it were, as
experts. We have had a long familiarity with
this question, and I contend that it is only
those who are ignorant of its true meaning
and significance who would hesitate to Indorse
the position which California has always taken
as a steadfast and patriotic opponent to the
further immigration of Chinese coolies.
It has been said in the East, where a propa
ganda against the re-enactment of the exclu
sion laws has been carried on, that the senti
ment of the country has changed; that even in
California, where, by the way, the Chinese
population, due to the beneficent effect of ex
clusion, has fallen from 76.000, acording to the
census returns in the year IS9O. to about 46.000
in 1900, it has been said that on that account
PRICE FIVE CENTS.
and on account of the opening, as It were, of
the Pacific by the victory of Dewey at Manila
Bay (Applause) that the people of the State
of California have also changed their views;
in other words, that the proponents of Chi
nese immigration have- taken advantage of
the effect of the exclusion law and of the in
terest that we all have in the opening of the i
Pacific, to insidiously, with the assistance of
the Imperial Minister of China at Washing
ton, Minister Wu, and the Imperial Consul
General at San Francisco, Mr. Ho Tow,
impress upon the minds of our Congressmen
and of our editors throughout the broad ex
tent of country ea3t of the Mississippi that it
would be diplomatic, that it would be la tho
substantial interests of this country, and
would be conducive to greater trade to let th«
exclusion act, which has been In force for
twenty years, die by legal expiration. When
we in San Francisco observed that a system
atic campaign was being made for the purpose
of undoing all the work for which w» had
straggled for twenty years, we deemed It nec
essary to call this convention; and I am sure
that none of you will resent the fact that 3*n
Francisco, your commercial emporluci, ha*
taken the leadership In this matter.
Our Commercial Emporium.
San Francisco is a commercial emporium.
It is like all commercial cities, perhaps, when
it comes to a matter of trade, unsentimental:
and it must impress Itself upon the people of
the East that if there is any advantage in
.Chinese Immigration we would not oppose It.
If it brought commerce to our warehouses and
to our marts there would be a very considera
ble element of our population thac would be
active In the demand which every commer
cial city makes for trade and more trade.
(Applause.)</text>
      </result>
      <result>
  <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1901-11-23/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Chinese+CHINESE+exclusion+EXCLUSION+Exclusion&st=text&r=-0.572,0.158,1.156,1.156,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CHINESE EXCLUSION CONVENTION
COMES TO A MOST BRILLIANT CLOSE
LOVES THE GOLDEN STATE.
THE Chinese Exclusion Convention
completed its labor? yesterday
after the adoption of one <>f the
most important as well as vipor
ous memorials on the Chinese
question ever addressed to the
President and Congress of the United
Elates. The attitude of the people of Cal
ifornia and of the entire Pacific Coast to
ward the problem of unrestricted immi
gration of Asiatics to these shores as rep
resented in the convention was distinctly
outlined, and its language cannot fail to
he understood in the East as being the
Fpontaneous outburst of a united people
n the imposition upon them i f a
grievous wrong.
The delegates gathered in force yester
day morning and listened with enthusi
asm to many speakers. Only one theme
was discuss-ei, only one idea advanced,
namely, unalterable resistance to the pro
ject of unrestricted Chinese immigration
to America. Tie danger of a Mongolian
invasion In the event of the refusal of
:ess to re-enact the exclusion law
wae pointed out in forceful language by
all the speakers. Assistant
Tnii^rj States District Attorney Duncan
E. McKinlay was introduced by the chair,
and that gentleman delivered an able ad
dress in which he reviewed the Chinese
question from the standpoint of the Dis
trict Attorney's office. The legal aspects
of the issue were capably presented, the
peakcr's remarks at times evoking
hearty applause. So favorably did he im
press his hearers that at the close of his
speech he was honored by a Tote of
thanks for his brilliant oratorical effort.
The Rev. Dr. William Rader followed
with a witty address, in which he re
viewed the Chinese question from the
standpoint of morality and religion. His
allusions to the vices prevailing in San
Francisco's Chinatown, and of their ef
fect upon the whole community, were im
pressively advanced, and his remark that
the proper place in which to Christianize
the Chinese was in China and not in this
country, evoked cheers. The address
was replete with statistical information,
and it was listened to with profound in
terest by all present.
Congressman Woods carried away the
banner by a characteristic speech in
which he informed the convention "that
with its assistance all h— l couldn't beat
the exclusion law." Woods was in deep
earnest, and all his utterances were ac
companied by vigorous gestures and a
beating of the rostrum with a vigor that
threatened to convert it into kindling
wood. He assured the convention that
the California delegation in Congress
would never give up the exclusion fight,
and when he sought to close what he
termed his "razzle-dazzle" address, the
crowd yelled lustily for more. Woods
obliged the delegates further, and when
he concluded the delegates gave him three
hearty cheers.
The closing address of the morning ses
sion was by Mayor Snyder of Los An
geles. During the afternoon the repre
sentatives of various labor organizations
SAN FRANCISCO, SATURDAY, NOVEMBER 23, 1901.
CONGRESSMAN WOODS ADDRESSING THE DELEGATES TO THE GREAT CHINESE EXCLUSION CONVENTION.
HIS FERVID REMARKS RAISED THE MEMBERS TO A HIGH PITCH OF ENTHUSIASM AND THEY
CHEERED HIM VOCIFEROUSLY THROUGHOUT HIS ABLE AND ELOQUENT SPEECH.
RE-ENACTMENT OF THE EXCLUSION
LAW IS DEMANDED BY CONVENTION
J yf HERE AS The Chinese exclusion act, known as the "Geary law," will expire by limitation
py May 24, 1902; and
Whereas, The treaty betzveen this country and China concerning the restriction of
immigration from the latter nation may, under its provisions, expire on March j, 1904; and
Whereas, The roils that produced the necessity for the enactment of the present exclusion lazy,
and the making of the present treaty with China, still exist in our midst, and dangers therefrom are
as imminent nozv as they were when the present barrriers zvere established; and
Whereas, Unless such barriers are maintained and vigorously guarded the invasion of
Chinese laborers, thereby checked, zvill expose our people to a renewal thereof, with all its influences
inimical to the interest of our zvage-earncrs and injurious to the general zvelfare; and
Whereas, The beneficial results flozving from the operation of the said act have met the expec
tations of the people in avoiding an increase of Chinese immigration and an aggravation of the many
ez'ils thereof, therefore be it
Resolved, By the Chinese Exclusion Convention of the State of California, composed of three
thousand delegates representing the State, county and city governments and industrial and civic or
ganisations in all parts of the State,
First That we demand the continuance of existing treaties ziith China and the re-enactment
of the "Geary exclusion law"
Second That we recommend that the California delegation in Congress act unitedly in the
presentation of the bill to accomplish the purpose hereinbefore set forth and use their utmost endeavor
to secure its immediate enactment into lazy.
delivered brief addresses. Dr. William
son, president of the Board of Health,
talked, of the Chinese curse in San
Francisco and frequently evoked ap
plause. Mr. Taylor of the State
Grange spoke in behalf ef the farmers
of California, and in a logical speech
showed the evil effects unrestricted im
migration of Chinese to California, would
exert upon rural pursuits in this State.
The main event of the afternoon session
was the reading and adoption of the me
morial to President Roosevelt and to
Congress. Prior to the filing of the re
port of the committee Supervisor Reed's
motion that a committee be appointed to
wait upon Rev. Father Peter C. Yorke
with the request that he address the coo
vention was carried, and Reed was de
tailed for the task. A motion to ad
journ just before Rev. Mr. Yorke's
arrival was voted down, and when
the clergyman appeared he was warmly
greeted. He spoke at some length, and at
the conclusion of his speech several mo
tions of more or less importance were
made and carried. The convention then
adjourned sine die.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
  <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1901-11-26/ed-1/?sp=12&q=act+Chinese+exclusion</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>This proviso looks suspicious in the face
of the appeal by the Chinese diplomats
that the exclusion laws.be. suspended for
that time "just as an experiment to see
v
how it will work." By that time Tarpey
and Bennett would have their steamship
lines operating and exclusion laws would
fail to keep the hordes of Mongolians
from crossing the border of Mexico into
the United States.
A prominent member of the local Mexi
can colony, In speaking of the matter,
said yesterday:
My country has no objection to the Chinese
for' we have a large territory to fill. But our
Government does not understand the Chinese
as the Americans do. We possibly have about
5000 Chinese in Mexico. The Government evi
dently took the tempting bait offered by Tar
pey and Bennett and is likely to secure the
passage of the bill by our Congress.
You cannot get a Chinese to remain in Mex
ico if he sees the slightest chance to get into
the United States. They have their relatives
in America and have heard how quickly
wealth is made in this big republic.
This talk of fishing privileges and canneries
to be erected is simply a blind to the eyes of
our Government. Of course there had to be
some excuse to land hundreds of thousands of
Chinese in Mexico and what more plausible
than that of the fishing privileges and can
neries. For one Chinese that might remain in
Mexico, ninety would slip across the border
into America.
If this country does not wish to see a Chi
nese invasion via the border line of Mexico
it must take immediate steps. A friendly sug
gestion by the American Government to the
Mexican republic that the proposed concession
to Tarpey and Bennett is objectionable would,
without doubt, secure the rejection of the
grant.
Chinese Guarantee $1,000,000.
It Is freely hinted at in certain quarters
that the Chinese residents in America
have guaranteed more than $1,000,000
toward the proposed plan of Tarpey and
Bennett and that the money will be put
up as soon as the concession is secured
from the Mexican Government.
With a line of steamships running from
China to Mexico and with the knowledge
that it Is almost impossible to guard the
American-Mexican border, the Chinese are
not likely to worry much as to how to
evade the extension of the exclusion laws.OTE ON CHINESE EXCLUSION.
Merchants' Association Takes Boli of
Members on Important Question.
The returns from a vote of the mem
bers of the Merchants' on
questions pertaining to the Chinese ex
clusion act are as follows:
Do you favor the extension of the present
Chinese exclusion act? Ayes, 425; noes, 208.
Do you favor a modified Chinese exclusion
act? Ayes, 243; noes, 376.
Do you favor sending delegates from the
Merchants' Association to the Chinese exclusion
convention? Ayes. 638; noes, 91.
Affirmative answers to No. 3, if pledged for
Chinese exclusion act Ayes. 11; noes, 0.
Affirmative answers to No. 3, if pledged
against Chinese exclusion act Aye-, 7; noes, 0.
Affirmative answers to No. 3, if pledged for
modified Chinese exclusion act— Ayes, 5; noes, 0.
Affirmative answers to No. 3, If pledged also
for Japanese exclusion Ayes, 1; noes, 0.
Parties desire matter to be left to board of
directors' discretion— Ayes, 4; noes, 0.
The delegates who were appointed by
the Merchants' Association to the Chi
nese Exclusipn Convention, are Prank J.
Symmes, Marshal Hale and Andrew M.
Davis.Chinese Exclusion Forms
Subject for Long
Debate.
The Unitarian Club listened last evening
to a debate betwen picked orators con
cerning the re-enactment of the law
which excludes Chinese from, the Lnited
States. The champions of continuing the
present policy of exclusion were Mayor
Phelan and Thomas J. Geary. The other
side was taken by- Chinese Consul Ho Tow
and Dr. Fryer of the University of Cali
fornia. President Gregory of the Lm
tarian Club presided at the debate which
took place after a dinner in the Mer
chants' Club rooms. Business and profes
sional men listened and applauded, lber-
a M*ivor Phelan opened the discussion. He
said that exclusion was the settled policy
oftheUmfed States ana had oeen sucxx
for twenty years. At the time 01 the
adoption ot tnl^urlingame treaty there
was an opinion that cneap Chinese labor
JrlJ* acted clearly in. obedience to the
S 9 of thf peopl. Ye Cmnese
ment by treaty consented to the exclusion
5 ?he Chinese from this country^
Thvre was ,no question that -the unitea
States had power to exclude any undesir
able class of immigrants. Paupers and
contract labor from Europe were sent
wa? whether the Chinese were desirable
shlp Old Slavery Spirit.
The that Inspired the bringing of
mmm
8111111
wmsmm.
would low^the standard of civilization in
'^Sl* H^Yow contended that the
Jvf ln ?m 000 Chinese in the country be
fore tS* tot- law ,to exclude them was
rested 'The question was introduces by
Sf P n who were speaking from soap. boxes.
An? student would know that the Chi
nese in the United States came from the
Son Province; which had only 20.000.
m inhabitants. If the exclusion law
should fail •to be re-enacted the effect
would be that only the Cantonese would
come here.
Advocates Servile i- Class.
Ttte first Chinese visited the United
States because they were persuaded to
do so by the Union and Central Pacific
railroad companies, which could not get
white labor to build their railroads.
When the roads were built the Chinese
laborers: were turned off to find employ
ment .or themselves.
Ho Vow asserted t.iat if there was no
exclusion act the Chinese,. could not com
pete with white labor. Every channel of
fife must be filled, he said. 1 If all were
rich there w would- be none to cook for
them or to do their washing; The coun
try needed the Chinese. to make it a suc
cess Speaking 'of the non-asslmllability
of the Chinese laborers with the Cau
casian, he said that it would be danger
ous for this country. to try to incorporate
any low element into society. Why did
England respect; the United States? Be
cause they were being undersold. China
had one-third of the _ population of the
Ho Vow insisted that Chinese exclusion
would interfere with the trade of the
United States with China. The Chinese
were not without sentiment and they re
sented an injury. During the recent war
with Spain the clothing manufacturers of
San Francisco could not "get white people
to work on the clothes for the American
soldiers at the price they wished to pay.
What would have become of the soldiers
if the Chinese 'r had not made their
clothes? The clothing manufacturers
would, say that .white people did not wish
to work f or a pittance. The Chinese as
laborers filled places that white people
did 5 not want.
Geary Opposes Ho Vow.
Thomas J. Geary attacked IHo Tow's
conclusions vigorously. He said that the
country .in the civil war clothed i and fed
1,000.000 men for years, without the aid
of Chinese •or any other people. Then
was carried on a, war to preserve a coun
try based upon manhood. Ho Vow had
spoken as it might be supposed he would,
for he represented a civilization ia which
one class enjoyed all the luxuries and the
other class served them. That was the
attitude of the men who fired on Fort
Sumter. Mr. Geary dwelt on the hl3- y
of the United States and held that 'Iw
institution of a servile class, such a? H'
Vow had suggested, could only end in
disaster to this country.
The trade argument Mr. Geary declared
to be a sham. China had 350,000,000 peo
ple steeped in poverty, who could not
buy the products of American mills. Ha
quoted figures to show that 30,000 white
men who might take the place of 30.000
Chinese would spend more than double
the value of the 3nnual exports of San
Francisco to China.
Dr. Fryer closed the debate. He ad
mitted that the United States could ex
clude whom it chose to exclude, but per
haps there would be an objection if the
Chinese Government should exclude
Americans from China.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
  <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/46032385/1901-12-06/ed-1/?sp=1&q=act+Chinese+exclusion</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>It will be necessary for the present congress
to. take acjtion upon the Chinese exclusion act
which expires by limitation May 24, 1902. The
Kjansas City platform contained the following
plank on the subject:
We favor the continuance and strict en-
forcement of the Chinese exclusion law and
its application to the samo classes of all
'Asiatic races.
This plank was unanimously agreed upon by
the platform committee, and there was no dissent
from it among the delegates. It is to be expected,
therefore, that the proposition to extend the
Chinese exclusion act will receive the support of
all the democrats in the house and senate. The
editor of The Commoner received a letter a few
days ago from a democrat who complained that
the laboring men of the Pacific slope had ignored
the. Chinese question in the last campaign and
suggested that it would only be a merited punish
ment if the republican party refused to extend the
exclusion act. It is not unnatural that some
resentment should be felt toward those who sup
ported the republican party in spite of the dangers
which republican supremacy involves, and yet no
one can justify himself in either supporting a bad
policy or in failing to protest against it merely be
cause the policy would punish .some who ought to
have exerted themselves to prevent ij:. That
many of the republican leaders are in favor of a
..policy, Jfcat will flood the country with cheap
Chinese labor, is true, and that an imperial policy
tends to lend encouragement to the cheap labor
proposition, is also true, but the failure of the
laboring men' to see these dangers in advance
would not justify .democrats in remaining quiet
on this subject, although the republicans are in
"power and are responsible for legislation.
The Chinese question is one that effects the en
tire country, not the Pacific Coast alone or the
laboring men alone. It is true that the Pacific
Coast would feel the evil effects of Chinese emigra
tion first, and it is also true that the laboring men
would come into immediate contact with oriental
labor, but in its ultimate influence the subject
touches all parts of the country and reaches all
classes. The question is whether we are going to
build up a strong, independent, upright and pa
triotic people and develop a civilization that will
exert a helpful influence on all the world, or
whether we are going to be a greedy, grasping na
tion, forgetful of high ideals and concerned only
in the making of money.
Chinese emigration is defended by two classes
of people. First, by those, comparatively few in'
number, who believe that universal brotherhood
requires us to welcome to our shores all people of
all lands. This is the sentimental argument ad
vanced in favor of Chinese emigration. There Is
no more reason why we should construe brother
hood to require the admission of all people to our
country than there is that we should construe
brotherhood to require the dissolution of family
ties. The family is a unit; it is the place where
character and virtue and usefulness are developed,
and from the family a good or evil influence ema
nates. It is not necessary nor even wise that the
family environment should be broken up or that
ill who desire entrance should bet admitted to the
family oircle. In a larger sense a nation is a
family. It is the center for the cultivation of na
tional character, national virtue and national use
fulness. A nation is under no obligation to the
outside world to admit any body or anything that
would injuriously effect the national family; in
fact it Is under obligation to itself not to do so.
The influence of the United States will bo much
more potent for good if we Temaln a homogeneous
nation with all citizens in full sympathy with all
other citizens. No distinct race like tho Chinese
can come into this country without exciting a fric
tion and a race prejudlco which will mako it moro
difficult for us to exercise a wholesome influence
upon the Chinese in China, not to speak of our in
fluence on other nations.
Let us educate tho Chinese who desire to learn
of American institutions; let us offer courtesy and
protection to those who come here to travel' and
investigate, but it will not be of permanent benefit
to either the Chinese or to us to Invite them to be
come citizens or to permit them to labor here and
carry the proceeds of their toil back to their own
country.
The second, and by far the larger class, em
braces those who advocate Chinese emigration on
the ground that it will furnish cheap labor for
household- and factory work. There is no force In
the argument that is made by some that it is diffi
cult to secure girls to do housework. If domestic
service is not popular as compared with other
w.ork, it is because the pay is not sufficient to mako
it attractive and the remedy lies in better wages.
Labor can be secured for any and every honorable
-position-when-the'i'4sufflcienfc-to'attratitr'
and the demand for Chinese servants comes with
poor grace from those who often spend on a sin
gle social entertainment as much as a servant'3
wages would amount to in an entire year. At this
time When skilled and intelligent American labor
is able to compete in foreign markets with the
cheapest, labor of the world, it is absurd to talk
about the necessity for cheap factory hands.
The increase in Japanese Immigration, or rath
er importation (for large numbers of them are
brought for specific purposes) has been referredto
in a former issue of The Commoner. IWwas there
suggested that the Japanese government would
doubtless, if asked to do so, place restrictions upon
Japanese emigration that would make it unneces
sary for us to deal with the subject by legislation.
This matter should at once be brought to tho at
tention of the Japanese authorities, and unles3
sufficient and satisfactory action Is taken by the
home government the Chinese exclusion act should
be made broad enough to extend to Japanese of
the same class.
The subject of oriental emigration cannot be
discussed without giving some consideration to
the danger of cheap labor from the Philippine isl
ands. It will soon be necessary to legislate on
this subject. If the Filipinos are permitted to
come here there is danger that the Philippine ques
tion will become only second in aggravation lo
the Chinese question. If, on the other hand, the
Filipinos are prohibited from coming here (if a
republic can prohibit the inhabitants of one part
from visiting another part of the republic), will it
not excite a just protest on the part of the Fili
pinos? How can we excuse ourselves if we In
sist upon opening the Philippine islands to the In
vasion of American capital, American speculators,
and American task-masters, and yet close our doors
to those Filipinos who, driven from home, may
seek an asylum here?
TIio democratic party should take a strong
and aggresslvo position on this question. It can
afford to'oppoBO Chinese emigration and insist
upon tho unity and homogoncousness of "oiir
nation. It can afford to Insist that Japanese la
borers shall be treated the samo as Chinese labor
ers and excluded, by agreement with tho Japanese
government if possible, by congressional legisla
tion if necessary.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
  <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1902-04-17/ed-1/?sp=1&q=CHINESE+Chinese+exclusion+EXCLUSION&st=text&r=-0.161,-0.085,1.337,1.499,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Turner .then entered upon a discussion
of the -merits of the. Chinese »exclusion
bill.,' He spoke of .the Chinese, declaring
that\twQ-facedness ;is. a characteristic of
that people,', from which not even the
Emperor is free. He: also declared .that
the great Chinese Viceroy who had re
cently died \_had';. amassed his Vcoiossal
fortune by the corrupt use of office, and
followed this i remark with the statement
that! if Chinese were to be admitted to
the United States upon -the certificates
of' Chinese^ officials; there .might.be .no
pretenseof a check upon.lt." rUTRNER ARRAldNS CHINESE..
I Turner \ofj Washington then proceeded,
'explaining a casual remark made", yester
'da'y/,' concerning.' the Republican party.
He -said', he had no bitterness f. toward
that !par ty and that he had been a mem
ber., of,! it so 'lbng >as- it> was true' to, 'its
principles. He declared that the
i;ow t v0n all occasions: prefers the^ dollar
to the man, and that this fact is dem-
-The President pro tem. laid before the
Senate a number of telegrams' bearing
.upon the Chinese bill.; -These messages
vwere all from the" Pacific Coast. sixty-one
of them being favorable to the Platt sub
stitute and~ twelve opposed to ;'it.-'
•Pursuant of yesterdayV agreement the
Senate .was 'called to. order at: 10 o'clock,
hours in advance of the usual hour
of meeting.' This hour was fixed in, order
to permit more extended debate on the
Chinese exclusion bHl prior to the voting
"on that measure.
GOES BACK AS NEW. BIIX.
The Senate failed to substitute' the
enacting clause 'of the House bill; for th'e
Senate measure, so that the bill 'now! will
go to the House as an "original measure
and from a" parliamentary standpoint will
have to he acted on and "treated the same
as though- the I louse ;had not. passed a
Chinese 'exclusion bill already. pThc vote' by which the substitute took
the .place of the originalwas ayes 48 to
noes 33. Once the substitution had been
made air the Senators joined in its sup
port, with the single^ exception of Hoar,
the substitute being passed,. 76 to 1. The
friends of the^ 1 substitute .'showed their
strength throughout the voting on amend
ments .that preceded final action and; sue-,
ceeded in preventing any 'material change
in' its features. Some minor, conditions
were made, admitting Chinese persons
connected with national expositions^ arid
providing for certiflcates\of Identification
of /Chinese l in our insular, possessions.
Otherwise, 'however, the. substitute was
adopted substantially in "the 'form thit
Platt presented it.
HgBfr*'' 5^ fr 9 m the^Paciflc Coast
States met defeat in- the Senate to-day,
and in its place was substituted a meas
ure' offered by Platt of ¦Connecticut;^ex
tending the provisions- of the' preserit*;ex
clusion law and also .applying .that^cx-'
elusion' to all insular territory under* the
jurisdiction of the" Uriifed States. 'J.
"W *W V ASHIXCTON, 7 April 16.—,
JH f The;.drastlc Chinese cx-
H H elusion bill originally</text>
      </result>
      <result>
  <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87065462/1905-06-21/ed-1/?sp=7&q=Act+Chinese+Exclusion</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
  <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024827/1905-06-30/ed-1/?sp=4&q=ACT+act+Chinese+CHINESE+exclusion+EXCLUSION&st=text&r=-0.314,-0.271,1.629,1.629,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE CHINESE
EXCLUSION ACT.
One of the big questions which is
agitating thit country at tho present
time is the Chinese exclusion act, and
the effect its rigid enforcement has
now and may have in the future, on
American commerce and trade in
China. The exportation of cotton and
cotton goods to China has grov-n from
almost nothing to $40,000,000 in a few
yca-s. Other lines of exports to the
celestial kingdom have shown very
large gams. The American manufac
turer is clamoring tor an open door
to the trade of China. The American
manufacturer has always been solf-
ifsh and in most instances, been ready
to sacrifice the good of the people to
his own profit and selfish ends. It
matters little to the manufacturer of
cotton goods in New England or the
south if the Pacific coast and adja
cent territory is overrun with cheap
Chinese coolies, the lowest strata of
Chinese life. 5f he can find a ready
and a profitable market for a few
more millions of dollars of cotton
goods and other products of his shops.
7"he cry for more liberal immigration
Jiws for the Chinese comes wholly
Irom the manufacturers. Tne people
of the Pacific coast don't want the
aan at any price. He is a men-
ace to this country and his very pres
ence exerts a contaminating in
fluence. It is impossible for him to
amalgamate with the people of this
country. He can not become a citizen
and ho has no desire to make this
land of the free his home and reside
here permanently. Personally he Is
as objectionable as tho negro of the
J south and if we must have cheap labor
1 let us give the negro a chance. "We
lave him with us and while he is not
.as skillful as the Chinaman or as In
dustrious, he Is by far the best cheap
laborer in the world.
The Chinese exclusion act has been
in operation for more than twenty
years. At tho time of its passage a
perfect horde of orientals were
streaming Into this country, over
running the Pacific coast states, and
drifting far back into the interior. The
exclusion act stopped this unholy in
vasion at once and the flow of China
men began to go the other way. There
were at that time more than a quar
ter of a million Chinamen In the
"United States. During these twenty
years this number has been on the
gradual decline. Death has thinned
tho ranks of the yellow skinned sons
of the east and a large proportion of
the Chinamen who were in this coun
try have made their "stake" and re
turned to China to remain. In San
Francisco. Los Angeles, Portland and
Seattle the gradual decrease in the
number of Chinese has been most
notable. It is doubtful if at the pros
sent time there are 50,000 Chinese in
the entire country, and the country
will be infinitely better off when
these, too, "have folded their tents,
like the Arab, and silently stolen
away."
The manufacturers, for years, have
kept an outrageous tariff on all
classes of manufactured goods by
their cry of "protection to American
labor," and they have filtched mill
ions of dollars from the pockets of
the people under the guise of a tariff
to enrich their own. It matters not
to them how heavy the burden on
the shoulders of the people, just so
they get their pound of flesh. Now
they wo ild throw wide open the doors
to the Chinese in order to get a few
more dollars of trade.
We very much mistake the fcentl-
ment of the American people if they
cater to such a cry or agree to admit
the Chinaman on any terms. Let the
door remain closed and barred to the
celestials of the east forever and if
more stringent regulations were
adopted In regard to immigrants from
other countries it would be better
and not worse for the country.
ft</text>
      </result>

      <result>
  <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86076200/1901-08-03/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Chinese+Exclusion+Act&st=text&r=-0.331,-0.083,1.661,1.661,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CHINESE EXCLUSION.
Miners' I nlon Petition* tor
enactment of the Present tow.
The Sentinel publisher below a lettei
from a oommittee of th# Tosoarors
Miners' Union together with a petition
which it to be presented to Congrast
asking the re-enactment of the Chinese
Exclusion Act. The petition should be
generally signed as the question ia one
which appeals to the people of th ie
State. The more against Chinese immi
gration has been started in the right
quarter—by the labor unions—aa the
laboring people will be the greatest suf
ferers ahonld the Chinese be permitted
to again invade this country
To the Kdltor of the Bxstinxl:
The within petition will in a measure
explain itself. The Chinese Exclusion
Aot will expire by limitation in May,
1902. As labor it the first to feel the
evil effects of the importation of cheap
labor and degraded workers, organized
labor baa decided to appeal, through
petition, to the people for a re-enact
ment of the Chinese Exclusion Act, with
mendments that appear in the petition.
We do not deem it necessary to argue
the question with the people of Nevada,
for we think they folly understand the
evils of Asiatio immigration and only
want the opportunity presented to act.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
  <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86090439/1906-01-19/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Chinese+Exclusion+Act&st=text&r=-0.38,-0.181,1.475,1.475,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
  <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84022137/1905-10-12/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Chinese+Exclusion+Act&r=0.017,0.683,0.678,0.38,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
  <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90061663/1904-04-21/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Chinese+Exclusion+Act&st=text&r=-0.463,-0.23,1.603,1.603,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>A bill
drawn by the Department of Justice,
which Bwcka to strengthen every weak
place in the Chinese exclusion act,
was Introduced In the House by Mr.
Hill, chairman of the committee on
forelsn affairs. The first section ob
viates any embarrassment on account
of the renouncement hv the, Phinat
rovernment of the treaty between the!
I nitea btntes covernmpnt and rhhi
by striking from the Chinese exclusion
act the words "If not Inconsistent
with treaty obligations."
Tlie second section permits the en
trance Into the United States of per
sons of Chinese descent who are citi
zen of the United State by birth,
also those who are specifically grantea
by law the privilege of admission "and
Do others The-words Thtnx rvrr.
on" or "person of Chinese descent"
are denned In the bill to mean "any
person descended from a Mongolian
ancestor which ancestor 1 now, ot
was at any time suhseauent to the
year 1S00. subject of the emperor of
China. The word "laborer Is con
strued to Include all neraona nf Mil,
nese descent not sneeirimllv nermlr.
ted by law to enter or remain within
the United State. The provision or
the act of 1S9.1. defining the word "la
borer" to embrace skilled and un
skilled manual laborers I repealed.
Another section of the bill extends
the Jurisdiction of officers of the gov
ernment by giving them the right to
J m i iur,lron or raci upon wc ch
rest a claim of citizenship set r.p br a
Chinese person, a they must deter
L oeier
decide questions of fact upon which
relating to the
admission of any alien.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
  <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86061215/1907-01-15/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Chinese+Exclusion+Act&r=-0.319,0.39,1.724,0.966,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>

  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-cocaine</id>
    <results>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042461/1898-12-11/ed-1/?sp=10&q=cocaine+drug+narcotic+dope+pills+toxic+addiction&st=text&r=-0.411,-0.064,1.265,1.265,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE COCAINE MONSTER
THROWING HIS TENTACLES
AROUND THE NATION
HOW IT GRIPS ITS VICTIMS
The Deadly Drug Whose Influence
Carries Men to Insanity and
Death Becoming Too Popular
Value of cocaine leaves imported at the
port of New York in 1894.114,384; imported
in 1807, #54.122; indicated value ot imports
for 18SKS, $75,000.
In these simple figures are contained the
elements of a warning sermon that would
startle all America. We seem to be rapidly
becoming a nation of cocaine fiends, it the
number of those addicted to the u.-e ol the
dreadful drug continues to increase at the
present rate the importation of what "as
originally regarded its a blessed alleviator
of pain will have to be classed with opium
ami its use prohibited by law, except tor
medicinal purposes.
At present the cocaine Bend can pill-chase
the drug without trouble and the case with
which it is taken is a fatal recommenda
tion to those who crave a nerve-dcadener.
No laborious cooking of pills over a lamp,
cleaning of implements or troublesome neces
sity for secrecy, as with the use of opium.
Cocaine can be taken at any time, with
scarcely any trouble, anil without a soul
besides the being aware ot his being
in the toils.
At first, that is. It will not be long before
every intimate friend will observe c change,
a gradual ami scarcely perceptible change,
come over the appearance and general con
duct of the cocaine fiend. II the one who
yields to the toxic influence of the drug be
a lawyer, then it will be noticed that Ilia
language as he pleads a case in court has
become particularly diffuse, while his argu
ments are long drawn out and lacking in
logic. Others will notice this peculiarity
and wonder. The victim will be in hli'siul
ignorance of anything wrong, for another
queer phase of the progress ot cocaine pots-
Suing is that il lulls the user into a de
lightful feeling of self-satisfaction, and,
whatever his shortcomings, he is contented
ami happy—until the influence of the drug
departs and leaves him only with the dead
ly craving for more that none can tight oil.
The lecturer who becomes a victim to the
cocaine habit will, to the surprise ot his
audience, spend the enure period allotted
to a certain subject on a single insignificant
part of it, or seem to tot get the topic en
tirely and wander into something entirely
foreign. It will strike the listeners that
the learned lecturer has been drinking or is
beginning lo get feeble-minded, there will
be nothing in lie appearance or manner of
the speaker to indicate that he himself has
the slightest knowledge that he lias not
been treating the subject in the brightest
and most careful way. Cocaine is a drug
that deludes its victims. It i- the very devil
blmsell in tin form of an innocent-looking
crystal, and the way the much-to-be-pitied
cocaine user is dragged slowly, but with
aw ml certainty, down, toinsanitsand death
is a terrible tribute to the strength ol the
demon that links in ihe drug.
This confusion oi ideas and language is
the first symptom of the toxic influence of
the cocaine beginning lo work. It you have
a friend in whom these symptoms are no
ticed, il might be well to find out il he is
addicted 10 the use of cocaine, tor at this
early stage the habit may be broken. Later
it is almost hopeless for the victim to try
to sunder his chains.
Begun in many cases in a legitimate way,
as an anesthetic, the surprisingly pleasant
effect is sought, lor again by the one who has
had a glimpse ai Ihe portals of elysium. This i
is tbe beginning of the terrible habit. The i
effect is a sense of exhilaration followed by a
quiet, dreamy state that causes the worried
man to forget his troubles and the sufferer i
his pain. nn,.,. this freedom from physical
and mental sickness has been experienced,
the cocaine fiend will t 01. or kill to get the I
ding. Enforced non-use of it will not cure
the victim. Sentence him to a term ot'im
prisonment, ami he will go straight from
the jail door to the nearest drug store to
secure cocaine before he eats or sleeps. i
This, of course, cannot last. From an
occcasional use of the drug to insatiable
craving is the rational course of the cocaine
fiend. From thence to the insane asylum i
anil the grave is a swift and easy descent. Edwin looks after
In his fall from health to physical and
mental disintegration the cocaine fiend un
dergoes a terrible experience. When not in
the temporary heaven that the drug pro
vides, the victim is in the lowest depths of
an infeino. He is subject to apprehen
sions, delusions and hallucinations. He suf
fers from insomnia, anorexia and gastralgic
latins, dyspepsia, chronic palpitations and
wiil-paresis. He is a terror both to himself
and others. The life of the man is a living
death. He knows it, nnd with this know
ledge -taring him in the face, he rushes for
the drug nnd is happy for a brief perftd
under its influence. It is time something
were done to keep from this high-strung
nation a drug so deadly. Clear-minded
medical men have recommended its exclu
sion from the country, believing that its use
medicinally should be foregone rather than
that such a cursed temptation should be
placed in tbe way of weak humanity.
"What tbe real action of the drug is, and
how to counteract its influence, aie at pres
ent puzzling questions to the medical fra
ternity. A lending member of the profes
sion to whom these questions were put re
plied, alter careful consideration, as follows:
lis physiological action is practically un
known. As an analgesic, it is uniform in
its action, and this is due'to the suspension
of the physiologic functions of the sensory
cells which it comes in contact with. Be
yond this, it is an excitant of the cerebro
spinal axis, later it has a peculiar ac? Tun
on the encephalon, manifest in a wide range
of physical phenomena. Beyond this a
great variety of widely variable symptoms
appear. In some cases all the intellectual
faculties are excited to the highest degree.
In others a profound lowering of the senses
Hid functional activities occur. Morphine
takers can use large quantities of cocaine
.vithou. any bad symptoms. Alcoholics
ire also able to bear huge doses without
lunger. Not infrequently the excitement!
taused by cocaine goes on to convulsions and
ieath. The cocaine User takes large quan
tities but in small doses frequently repeated.
:He becomes frightened at the effects of
huge doses, and when be cannot get the
effects from small (to him safe) doses, he
resorts to alcohol, morphine or chloral. In
many cases memories of the delusions and
hallucinations are so vivfd and distressing
i that other narcotics are used to prevent
their recurrence. In other cases the recol-
I lection is very confused ami vague, and
I strong suspicions rill tbe mind that the real
condition is grossly exaggerated by the
friends for some deterring effect. In com
mon with opium and alcoholics there is
moral paralysis, untruthfulness and low
cunning m order to conceal and explain the
condition by other than the real causes.
The prognosis is always doubtful when the
addiction has continued any length ol tune.
The temporary removal of the drug and
restoration of the case occurs In nearly till
cases, but unless a radical change of life and
li\ ing is made, and the patient gives un
usual care to his health and to tbe avoidance
of every source of exhaustion of nerve and
brain, and every condition of peril to his
health, the danger of relapse is very prom
inent.
"The treatment must be pursued on gn:
eral principle-. Isolation and removal of
all exciting causes and building up of the
brain and nervous system comprise the gen
eral principles. In every case certain spe
cial localized means are essential to meet
the various conditions present. The Midden
removal of the drug is' the tirst step.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87093039/1911-05-12/ed-1/?sp=3&q=cocaine+drug+narcotic+dope+pills+toxic+addict</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>DANGERS Of DEADLY COCAINE
Rapid Increase of the Most rnsidioiis Drug
Habit—The Craving Usually Acquired by
Accident
With the month of May comes the
opening of the six months harvest of
the soda fountains. "What will you
have?" asks the amiable clerk and
points to a list of sirups, a row of gayly
colored bottles and some large bowls on
the counter containing crushed straw
berries, sliced pineapple and other
I tempting fruits. If you stick to the
fruit sirups and the fruit is really good,
no harm is done. On the contrary-
But if you turn to the bottled attrac
tions or listen to the promise of their
much advertised qualities, then beware.
Here is plain warning from Dr. L. F.
Kebler, chief of the division of drugs
in the government bureau of chemistry:
"Attention is directed to the danger of
soft drinks containing caSeine, extract
of kola nut and extract of coca leaf, the
active principle of the two latter being
cocaine."
According to Dr. Kebler, scores of
soft drinks, dangerously medicated, are
sold at soda water fountains as stimu
lating and refreshing summer drinks
without the slightest intimation to pur
chasers that their stimulating and re
freshing qualities come from cocaine, a
drug that produces one of the worst
habits known to the medical prefession.
"We have seen," said Dr. Kebler,
"how the opium habit may be acquired
by the use of various proprietary or se
cret preparations usually employed as
domestic remedies, and so the cocaine
habit may be developed by the use of
these much lauded soft drinks."
During a recent visit to Washington
I talked with two heads of departments
in the bureau of chemistry, both active
in government prosecutions of drugged
soda water sirups. "There is no ques
tion," said one of these authorities,
"that the presence of cocaine in soft
drinks tends to create in the consumer,
whether child or adult, a predisposition
towards the cocaine habit."
It is evident that the manufacturers
of these soft drink sirups have only one
motive for putting cocaine into them
that is to make them popular, to make
them taste good, to make them sell
better. And this popularity, this pleas
ant taste and better sale come simply
and solely because there is enough co
caine in these soft drinks to give some
thing of the stimulating and exhilarat
ing effect that cocaine always gives.
"It is not uncommon," says Dr.
Kebler, "to find persons addicted to the
use of medicated soft drinks. It is a
well known fact that many factory em
ployes, stenographers, typewriters and
others subject to mental or nervous
strain spend a part of their earnings for
drinks of this character. Parents, as a
rule, withhold tea and coffee from their
children; but, having knowledge of the
presence of cocaine, caffeine or other
deleterious agents in soft drinks, they
unwittingly permit their children to be
harmed by their use."
Cocaine —what is it? The Standard
Dictionary tells us: "Cocaine, a white,
bitter, crystalline alkaloid contained in
coca leaves; used in medicine as a
local anesthetic." And again: "Coca,
the dried leaves of a South American
shrub of the flax family, used in medi
cine as a tonic; chewed by tne native i
Indians as a nervine stimulant." There
is no connection between the coca
shrub and the cocoa palm tree that pro
duces cocoa nuts.
An ounce containg 480 grains and a
grain of cocaine is a dose. From a
single source of cocaine supply in New
York city 480,000 doses of this dan
gerous drug were illegitimately dis
pensed every month.
How is the habit usually acquired?
"By accident, like other drug habits.
I'm sorry to say that one of these —er
—accidents is the presence of cocaine
in catarrh medicines." Dr. Podstata
proceeded to give me details in the
case of one of his patients, a man of 22,
who became a cocaine fiend quite inno
cently by taking a widely advertised
"catarrh cure" that contained only a
small percentage of cocaine, but, alas,
enough to establish the habit. The
young man sniffed his "catarrh cure"
up his nose, and after each sniffing ex
perienced a characteristic sense of ela
tion, a peculiar well being. He took
more and more of the stuff and soon
{discovered that his exhilaration came
from cocaine in the powder. Now, it
was cocaine he wanted, not the catarrh
cure; and presently he began to take
the drug pure, sniffing it, after the man-
i ncr of adepts and finally learning to use
jit in hypodermic injections. Soon he j
learned that the sensations were not at I
all pleasant. Far from it! Quick after
each period of intoxication came the
i dread of reaction that calls for more and i
always more cacaine. The character
istic physical and moral deterioration
went on rapidly. The victim grew sal
low-faced, sunken-eyed, restless, irrita
ble. He lost ambition and persever
ance. He became a liar, a wreck, help
less and useless, and within a year he
was placed in an asylum.
Notice that all this came to pass be
cause a perfectly well-meaning young
man bought at a reputable drug store
in Chicago what was advertised as an j
excellent cure for catarrh. And before
he knew what he was doing and taking
he had become a "coke fiend" and his
life was irretrievably ruined.
At Hull House, that haven of good
works in Chicago, I found impressive
corroboration of the statement that chil
dren easily fall into the cocaine habit.
Dr. Hamilton, a woman bacteriologist
of Hull House, made an investigation
among boys and young men in the
neighborhood and found that numbers
of them were regular users of the drug.
Dr. Hamilton found that the cocaine
habit had spread through one group of
seven boys. The youngest,Willie, was
coming home from school one day when
a negro who offered him a sniff of pow
der, saying it would make him feel
good. Willie sniffed the powder and,
as he expressed it, felt like a million
aire. The negro sold him what was
lelt of the powder in a little pill box
for IS or 20 cents, and told the boy he
would be around that corner every even
ing with more of the stuff. He also
suggested that Willie inform his boy
friends of the wonderful effects of this
powder. Willie went back to the cor
ner and bought more of the drug. He
wanted to feel like a millionaire. He
told his two brothers, young men of 17
and 18, and they tried the powder.
One by one four of their friends were
initiated until the group of seven was
formed. All seven became absolutely
demoralized; they quit going to school,
stopped work, stayed away from home
all night, going on regular cocaine de
bauches and spending as much as $7
in a single day for the drug. When
their money gave out they would pawn
their clothes, they would steal, they
would do anything to get more money
to buy more cocaine.
Through the earnest efforts of the
Hull House people these seven boys
were cured of the habit. Dr. Hamilton
thinks a cure is possible for the young,
though rarely possible for adults. Even
so, the effects of their long indulgence
in cocaine did them permanent injury.
Their power of resistence was enfeebled
and three of them died of tuberculosis.
It is a question, too, whether the others
have been quite sound mentally.
I talked with a husband and wife,
both "coke fiends," whom I found in
a filthy hovel on "Cocaine alley," the
foulest part of Chicago, and they both j
assured me that they thought nothing
of spending 84 or 85 a day for "dope." j
They might lack food, clothing, warmth,
decency, everything; but without co
caine they could not and would not
live. This husband, strange to say,
was a man of intelligence and nice in
stincts. He wore glasses and had a
fine brow. He was a carpenter by trade
able to earn good wages until he got
this habit. His wife, a shattered, shriv
eled, frantic creature (she was on the
verge of the cocaine "leaps" informed
me with a certain pride that she had
once been a famous dancer in the Black
Crook company.
In an adjoining hovel was a colored
—a tall, lithe, wild-eyed victim, who
said a dollar's worth of cocaine was only
enough for a few sniffs, it would scarcely
last an hour.
Pure cocaine, which is manufactured
freely in various cities, is worth about
84 an ounce. That is what crooked
cocaine merchants pay for it. Then he
retails the drug by the little pink pill
box full, or the little blue bottle full,
and by thus subdividing it gets for each
ounce 820 or 825. That is, when he
sells the stuff pure to those who want it
for "hypos" and know the difference;
but to the "sniffers" he sells the drug
half adulterated with acetanilid, a very
cheap powder that looks like cocaine,
and allows him to double his gain.
I Sometimes these vulture retailers will
work off on very desperate, half-crazed
"fiends" a quality of "dope" that is
two-thirds adulteration, which gives the
dealers a profit of 860 an ounce!
No wonder a flashily-dressed negTO,
known as the "coke king of Chicago."
i boasted that, if the police would leave
I him alone for a single year, he would j
retire with a fortune. And no wonder
Ihe has been able, by the devices of
well paid lawyers, to get himself speedily
out of the Bridewell every time he has!
been sentenced there. Residents on j
the mean street where this nogro lives I
will tell you of smart automobiles draw
ing up before his close-barred, dingy
shanty, and of well-dressed men or veiled I
j women hurrying through the alley to a
1 back door. They knock and the door
I opens slightly. The caller deposits a
coin in the hand that appears in the
i opening and receives in return a small
box of cocaine. A chain guard pre
vents the caller forcing the door open
more than a few inches. It is always j
quite a trick, the detectives say, to
I "catch these cocaine dealers with the
goods."
A handsome Southern girl, daughter
of a judge, is a typical case. On her
father's death the family was left in
need, and this girl came to New York
and went on the stage Her beauty
and slender figure, together with a nat
ural charm, gave her advancement and
things were going excellently when she
was taken ill. The company was travel
ing at this time, and to relieve her pain
and allow her to play her part, a doctor j
gave her cocain. That was the begin
ning and the end is not yet. She mar
ried a few months later, and her hus-
band soon discovered she had the drug
habit. For years he has tried to break
her of it, but nothing has availed. She
is still a young woman with some of j
her old charm; but people notice that,
she is queer. She is unreliable; in fact
it seems impossible for her to tell the
truth. She has suffered a startling
physical change. Her face is pallid and
she stares at you with a frightened, fur
tive look. She is very thin, and they
say she hardly ever sleeps. She is
careless of her appearance and seems
(Continued on Opposite Page.)
Order to Shun ause on Salr of Keal
Kalate.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text>District Attorney Cropaey began hia
j iidive pursult of the cocaine sellers by
Interesting Deputy Commissioner
i Walsh in the matter. They intend to
keep after these lllegal merchants un
til they dean up Brooklyn.
We have already recelved reports
from wholesale houses that the sale of
the drug has been greatly redu. ed,"
naid Mr. t'ropsey yesterday, "and lt is
eartaJa that our flfty-elght convictlotiH
have stirred up the tranVkers in co?
caine ao that many of them are giving
lt up as a bad Job to taekie in Brook?
lyn."
Urgea More Draatic Penalty.
The District Attorney of King*
County belleves the law should be
made more drastlc, but declures re
sults ii.ay eaelly be obttalned under
the present law lf the police actually
do the work they are supposed to do.
"I belleve that an amendment mak
lng the poasesston of cocaine, without
n physl'ian'H preacription, a felony ln
itself, without Inslstlng that the prose
cution prove the possessor Intended to
MU lt, would be a good addltion to the
lnw. and I belleve the punlshment
should be lncreased from the present
llmlt of one year's lmprlaonment to
something like flve years," he said.
Mr. Cropsey thought that prison sen
tences of some length were probably of
more ubc ln curlng the vtctlms of the
cocaine habit than any other possible
retnedy.
ln this connectlon the fsct standsout
that one of the chlef things prison
keepers have to contend with ln carlng
for their prlsonera ls to keep them from
obtalnli.g cocaine. Bo prevalent Is this
habit among criminals that cocaine
has even been sent bllndly Into filng
Sing prison by outslders without any
knowledge that lt would reach their
own frlends wlthln.
Warden Kenncdy, of Sing Sing. told
a Tribune reporter re< ently that on one
occaslon he had bought a few eamp
halrs neoeasary for extra a**ats In the
ehapel. and though the transactlon was
handled entlrely by the prison authorl
ties. he thought of the poaslbillty of
cocaine smuggllng, and had the chalrs
carefully examlned on arrlval.
Ha found each chair had had n smnll
hole bored iu the woodwork. whleh had
b.-en filled with cocaine. then carefully
covercil up nnd vnrnished over. Inves
tlgatlon ea to the source of this pros
paettVO gift to the OOC-Joa users iii th?*
prison had led nowliere, because the
dealer who supplled the chalra could
ot flnd at. what Btage of their handling
the drug bad been hldden.
Tlv warden aald hla guards had
found cocaine hldden In the backa of
ii alr brushes sent to convlets by friends
OOtBlda. They had found lt even on
poatenrda. where lt had been hldden in
minute quantitlee under the stamp; in
the mlddle of clgarettes sent In to mn
victs, and even ln the hatbanda jf
visitors who came to see them.
l'ractically the same condltlona are
true ln the prlaona on Blackwell's Isl?
and, and even in the TombB, where
men are not conflned for long periods.
Taft Urgaa Congresa to Aet.
The world-wlde peril in the growth
of cocaine, oplum and other drug
habit*, which was the reason for the
calllng of a apeclal internatlonal con?
ference on the aubject at The Hague
last summer, recelved promlnent men
tion ln Prealdent Taft's message to
Congress yesterday. Bills are In pros
pect in the preaent Congress over which
both State and Treasury departments
hav worked. and which will probably,
aui.ng oth-r tbinge, put a ,_.-k to iu-1
Idruggists denounce
j cocaine law laxity
,_
Divided Responsibility for Enforcement Per
mits Vile Traffic to Flourish in
City, They Declare.
Another factor favoring the sellers of
coeatofl ln this clty came to lisht yeste
day, as The Trlbune's expositlon of the
prevalence of the tratfle ln tlie deadenlr.g
drug began to slnk into the minds of pub?
ng the aale of drugs should be placed In
the handa of the Hoard of Pharmacy, and
that th.- board should be given amole
means and provide.l wlth a r-ufflclent
number of inspectors to enforce the law
In every respect. Without such means
the board Is helpless.
"There can be no question of the need
of the most severe restrlctlon of the sale
of cocaine. The retall pharmacists w?re
th? first to rcallxaj the need of restrktloP
on the sale of hablt-formlng drugs. I
lntroduced a resolution at the 8t. Louis
meeting of the American Pharmaceutlcal
Association, ln 1901. provldlng for the
polnfment of a commlttee to considcr tbfl
uuestlon of the acqulrement of drug
baMtfl and the best niethods of legislatlvo
regulatlon of the dunger. .lo a wh-.le lot lf they want tO Klt Furmerly the exertitlon of the cocaine
laa v..i* under the Board of Phannacy.
and when we held the power we? dflBD?l
the rMaton out. B-it now the board has
nothing to d?> wlth the matter.
We agreed to the amendment making
the poOflflflflbM of the drug without a
dOOtOffl prescription a felony, because It
?BflOMd an If tli.it was a more effectlve
method Of reachlng the seller who trled
to p.iss himself off n_ a us r of the drug.
I'lithr tbal amendment thfl druggist ls
roqalrfld to flll out a cocaine sale certlfi
rate, and lf any one Is OBBgM wlth 10
eaJBfl OB his person without one of thes*.
i certltlcates be Is llable to $.V?D line or one
year's imprisonma-nt, or both.
Hintt at Cocaine Oraft.
?There Is no doubt ln my mlnd that
the police could flBfflfCfl ?be present law
wlth a great deal of case lf they wanted
to The trouble la tnat tbflf JOB't Al
though there ls no way of provlnf lt. lt
terstate flhlpments of these drug". ex?"Cocaine flends can wlthstand the rav
aKcn of the drujr." Dr. Cluldfoy t-ald, "for
from flfteen to thlrty ya*ars, and aoma
tlmes longer. 1 have h'ard of cases where
men got over tb<* habit after beeomlng
slaves to lt, but I have never heard of a
wornan flend belng able to Btop lt uaa
once she became addlcted to the drug."</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1912-12-06/ed-1/?sp=2&q=cocaine+drug+narcotic+dope+pills+toxic+addict</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BOSTON IN COCAINE WAR
Dance Halls Make "Fiends" of
Schoolgirls?Two Arrests.
Boston. Dee. 5? The revelatlon that
young alrle. aoma not yet out of aehool,
ara belng made "drug flenda" through
cheap dance halls and men who haunt
tham felllng cocaine has stlrred the
pollce to a vlforous campaign.
Two men were sentenced ln the munlcl
pal court for aalllng cocaine lllegally
Their arreats were the flrst of a aerlea
whieh tha poliee plau to make.
Infonnation had reached the pollce that
the users of tha drug IMM beeoming
more numerona. Pollce offleers wt-re aent
to mlx wlth those attendlng cheap dames.
It was found that men frequented tha
halls and sold to the dancers a "dash,"
the alang for aa lnjectlon, for price*
raaglng from 16 to 26 cents. The aquad
dlseov?red that many girls at danoea took
the drug for a lark at flrat. and then be?
fore long became conflrmed ueers of
morphlnt or "coke."
John Chambera. twtnty-eight vears old.
of Tremont atrefct, and Davis Hexton, of
No. 22 Fpton street. were the two whom
Judge SulHvan sentenced. Chambera waa
charged wlth having dellvered morphlr.e
to an ageut of the Watch and Ward So
eiety and alao wlth having tha drug ln
his posaeaalon. Father Flynn haa been an ardent
worker against the Insldloua growth of
the cocaine traffic in hia pariah, and hia
campaign haa dleclosed to him that the
agents who promote it have not
scrupled to create a demand for It
among children between thlrteen and
seventeen years old.
"I know of at least 100 children be?
tween thlrteen and seventeen years old,"
said Father Flynn, "who have been
habltual cocaine or heroin users. They
cven rarry it into their schoolrooma,
concealed in hollow penclla and watch
cases. and, in Bome inatancea, in fake
handages which were wrapped around
suppoaed cuts on their flngers."
The clergyman said that he had no
douht whatever but that the coacaine
sellera. eapeclally those who sold the
drng to young girls, were in league
with the agenta of the "white alave"
traffic.
"I know that young girls have been
Btupefled with the drug and then taken
to dlsorderly housea," he said, "and I
belleve that the agents of the 'white
ala\e' traffic are behind the cocaine
trafflC Hanglng is too good for theae
wre'ches. Qod help the poor souls too
weak and the young mlnds too frail te
grasp the terrlble meanlng of thia habit
and its awful conaequences."
Father Flynn has organlied a boys'
club ln his parish on non-dcnomina
tional llnes whlch now has three hun
dred members. Every one of theae
young fellows Is pledged to report to
Fhthcr Flynn cven the most apparently
trlfiing suaplclous clrcumatances which
he observes along the linc of cocaine
selllng.
Priait Finds Boy 8tupefied.
'1 have been able to save young fel?
lows, mere boya, and Bome glrla be
cnuse of the help these reports frou.
my boya gave me," sat"Juat I few nights ago I waa told of a
boy who waa walking along the street
ln a hnlf stupefied condition, and when
I found him he had twelve 'decks' of
ocalne ln his pockets. I took him to
my own physlclan, as I have taken
twenty i hildren wlthln the last fev
mo ithgj and hr is now under treainient
that will break the hablt."
Cocaine ia being aold in randy atore.
and small frult atores as well aa drurc
atores in the Brownsville section, Fa?
ther Flynn said, and it will take the
most vlgoroua klnd of a campaign to
eradlcate it.
"Probahly the most pltlable fenture
of this despicable traffic is tlie street
seller, who not only supplles the drug
to coiiflrmed users, but slso goes out of
hia t\ay to Induce young people, boys
and girla, to try it. so aa to make th.
ooatonaan also," he said. "I have re
c. ived complaints from parents 'hat
their (hildren aeemed to be dull in
their arhool work, and when I would
talk to the tatchatl about the i aaea I
would be told that the teachera had
n.ade up their mlnds that the children
had been kept up late at night, or had
too maiiv dutiea around the home.
"Purther Investigatlon dlacloaed that
these backward children were cocaine
fiends, aad ln avety case i found that
th^ir flr>t acquaintance with the drug
had lumo from a chance encouoter
with one of the street sellera, who had
IndUOad tliem to try lt OOOO.'Callinan waa arrested on B*pt*mber A
last ln a bllllard room at No. 2269 8eavenne with fmr other men. Opium and
cocaine were ftund on the prlsoneis, and
in their search for more of the druga tlie
detectlves who made the rald rlpped off
the baaeboard. Beneath It they found
two revolvers, i aandbag. a stlletto and
more opium.
Callinan was ronvlcted of the sam* of
fence ln 1*10 and tentenced to four months
in the penltentlary. In June, 1J?12, he waa
agaln arrested for havlng cocaine ln his
possesslon. He told James A. Delehanty,
an Aaaistant Diatrlct Aitorney, at that
tlm* that he waa not a "coke ttend" and
that he would break hlmself of the hablt.
He alao offered to glve whst help he
mlght toward the arrest and convlctlon
of cocaine sellera.
With Detectlve Dltseh, of Police Head
quartera. and Inspeetors from the Board
of Health, h* called on Dr. Abraham A.
lArvy and, lt ia alleged, bought a quan
tlty of cocaine frqm Dr. Levy wlthout a
preacrlptlon and gave him marked billa
in payment therefor. Dr. I.?vy 1s now
under indictment. and his caae 'a con
*lderrd by the Diatrlct Attorney to be
the atrongeat that has been prepared
agalnat a vender of cocaine aince the law
was amended.
OEMOCRAT8 LEFT $373 UNSPENT.
Washlngton, Dec. I -The atatement of
recelpts and expendlturea of the Deino
cratk Natlonal Congreas Commlttee
ahowa $12,?45 ln contributlona, nioatly In
small amounta. and a balance on hand of
tm. The Weatern branch ot the com?
mlttee reportcd t2S,2M |n contributlona
aad t2t,Mf iu expendlturea.
COCAINE BROUGHT IN
BY STR1KE BREAKERS
Former Chief City Food Inspector Says Cuban
Negroes Intiroduced the Vice in
New York.
The "coke" habit is the coming evil of
this country, unless strenuous and lmme
dlatc measurefl are taken to suppress it,
accordlng to Bayard C Fuller, who re
tlred a year ago last Juiy as chlef food
Inspector of the clty's Department of
Health, after twenty yeara of eervlce in
that department. For about flve yeara
before hia retlrement. he aald yesterday,
he made relentless war on the cocaine
traffic ln this city, maklng between two
hundred and three hundred arresta ln the
last three years of that period.
"Duiing lhat time," Mr. Fuller contln
ued. "we made more arrests In a month,
on the average. than the pollce did in a
year. The two men who helped me moat
?and too great pralae cannot be be*tod
upon them for their stand in the inatter
-were Maglstrate 'Joe' Corrigan and
Matristrate 'Harry' Stclnert, new a Judge
of Speclal Sesslons.
"The habit flrst got a hold in this a number of years ago. when thero was
a big strlke on the Ward llne of at. aniers
and the company Imported negroes from
JIavana to take the places of the strlkers.
I wasn't chlef Inspector at that time, and
mv duties used to take me down along
the wharve*. where I would see these hlg
blaek fellows lylng aiound hopelessly un?
der the Influence of the drug.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1914-02-15/ed-1/?sp=29&q=cocaine+drug+narcotic+dope+pills+toxic+addict&st=text&r=-0.253,-0.005,1.505,1.505,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>DRUG TE
R-ROR
PICTORIAL
MAGAZINE
Cnpiiriilhl, 1M I. hi) the
Sun I 'mi 1 1 ii a mill
I'ulillxhiiiil X.snirinlloit.
V
ilk

DOPE i
A dupe fiend cooking
his meal.
Drug dealers have
grown prosperous
on this type.
With Practically
Unrest ricted
Traffic Cocaine
Vice Has Grown
So Swiftly That
We Are Most
Drugged Nation in
World With 4.45
Per Cent, of Popu
lar on Addicted to
Habit
Hitting the Pipe."
Tons of opium im
ported for "medicinal
purposes" are used
for this purpose.
Campaign Under
taken by Mrs. Will
iam K. Vanderbilt,
Sr., for Extermina
tion of Practice One
of the Greatest
Moral Struggles in
History Cocaine
and Heroin Dead-
?k lies t of Habit Form
n r Coulter and a staff of investigators to
ue 1 'ui- campaign for the extermination of drug
adili' 'mil not only in the city and State of New York
but 'l.ioughout the United States.
So swiftly has this vice grown that tho United
States -iiis distanced every other nation in tho world
in tin Imu j,er capita of its illegitimate drug con
mip .in The commerce in cocaine, heroin, mor
pliiin im opium now approximates the opium traffic
of i 'n n China history's most notorious example
of .i I, -god nation when after 200 years of its com-
opiurn 0.5 per cent, of China's population
id to be opium smokers. With tho aid of
,y every civilized nation in tho world China
v reduced that figure to 4.1 per cent., while
d States twenty years of practically un
traffic in drugs has made drug addicts
'ent. of tho population.
v ii the United States tho scene of tho
.itest drug traffic but cocaino and heroin,
t invito use is peculiar to Americans, are
-,ie deadliest of tho world's I abit forming
morphine victim would experi nco no
1 I'ever from the daily drug do s of tho
riian e ca chewer, the AraVan hasheesh
Chinese opium smoker. But a morphine
live twenty years and do hii work, whilo
an eocaiii" addict turns cr'minal nnd No other vieo renders its victim so dangerous.
Opium, morphine und hasheesh pond their viutims
searching fo solitude, but u sniff of cocaine after
lifting Its victim into a half hour's losy overestima
tion drops him into tho streets and alleys in a state
of dangerous melancholia. So brief is the drug's
effect that it ta' es from i to u day to satisfy a
cocaine addict more nion y lian any other" drug
addiction exacts, That's why "coke" produces more
criminals in the city of New York than any other
single cause.
No other country in tho world knows the cocaine
habit. "Cocaine addiction is an American habit,"
says Dr. Charles U. Towns of 110 West Kighty-first
street, a recognized authority. "It is tho result of
our high pressure of living, our craving for over
stimulation, our proiienoss to 'take something' when
wo don't feel well. I have never known an Italian, a
Hungarian, a Itussiau, a Pole and only a few Jews
(except in the underworld) who took drugs."
"Cocaine addiction is the easiest habit to acquire
and the hudest to cure," say- Dr. PoiNtata, a Chi
engo drug expert. "Nothitur so iii kly deteriorate
its victim or provides o short a cut to the in-ano
asylum," says Dr. Towns, liccnu-c it takes such a
liiick, deadly grip of its victim then- ate some physi
cians who refuse to ndmini-tcr any cocaine what
ever', even ill legitimate medical piuctiee Yet any
crook can bring a carload of cocaine fiom Philadel
phia into New York city, and the Interstate Com
merce Commirsion is owerless to interfere.
Notwithstanding its vitiating effects the growth
of cocaine add.etiou is indicated by the i:tc, easing
import into the United States of coca leaves, the
only source of cocaine and tin product of a shrub
which cannot be grown here. According to t e
American Pharmaceutical Association the oca iri
Iort from l.S'JS to 11102 inclusive was valued at fM.'.'l 1,
from lWO to 1007, inclusive, $1.11111 liini. The ;r it
annual cousin ptiou of cocaine i L'nn.nno u ce-.
which 02 per cent, is used illegitimately ior 1 ve.y
man, woman and child in the United State-, a s
of cocaino sufficiently strong to kill -evera! m d.i"
Its enormous profit explains the growth of t'.e
cocaine business. An ounce of cocaine, wholes...
costs about $1. Divided into pink pill boxes 111, d I
bottles the ounce is sold without adulteration l"r
from $20 to to tho-e who use the needle and ki on
tho difference. Adulterated heavily wit iicetani'..!
it is sold to "sniffers" lor from J into $v 1 ounce and
half crazed fiends on the verge of the "1 u nine leap-"
can be made to yield even gi eater piolit. Thus
profits ranging from .VX to i,.VM per cent, on the
investment have entrenched the cocaine business
011 a nationwide scale.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1914-02-15/ed-1/?sp=30&q=cocaine+drug+narcotic+dope+pills+toxic+addict</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The widespread net' of cocaine In
tlie comparatively short period of
time since It.i discovery," sas J)r.
Towns, "has been brought about by
patent preparations coutalr'ng small
quantities of II."
During Its tlrst few years cocaine nd
illction spread through the wld" soli' of
"catarrh cures." which contained from 2
to 4 per cent, of cocaine. These "cures,"
according to Samuel Hopkins Ad. mis In
Ciilliri'i UVi'Afjr, were "Dr. Ilirncys Ca
tarrh Cure," "Dr. Colo's Catarrh Cure."
"Dr. Agnow's Caiairh Powder" and
"Crown t 'atari li Powder." Not only did
these "euro." Introduce many pcions
Into depth of cocaine addiction, but
they pointed the way to a method of j
taking cocaine easier than by hypo- 1
dermic.
For u time It became the practice to
fill Willi the "cure" a small bottle1
through the cork of which had been In-M-r'etl
it wo tubes, one of which was
placed In the mouth and the other In
the nostril; u puff from' the mouth did
the rest. Later It became the custom to
sprinkle the "cure" on. the back of the
hand and either 'to touch It to the
tongue or to sniff It onto the mucous
membrane of the nostrils. Tims the
deadliest of all vices became the Minplcsl
to begin.
Among the thousands who contracted
cocaine addiction through the innocent
putchase of a patent medicine was Mrs,
Anna .Meyers, who was prominent
socially In Chicago and In lsim was a
member of the board of managers of
the Chlcngo World's Fair. In a confes
siou detailing the career of crime Into
which cocaine plunged her Mrs. Meyers
Mays: "I used to get the little boxes of
the drug and call it 'my baby' and 'my
only friend,' cry over It and laugh and
dance like an Insane person."
It Is asserted that per cent, of
America's drug addicts learned their
vice In a doctor's olllce. Hundreds of
disreputable physicians make a practice
of giving morphine promiscuously for
their patients' iicIick, out of their olllees
Issues a constant procession of young
drill, addicts "Not more than 10 per
cent, iif all the drug addicts have any
incurable disease that would Justify fur
ther use of the drug." says Dr. Towns.
The use of drugs has crept Into colleges,
where students take them tn counter
act the effects of overwork; tfiey liavo
crept Into the army, where soldiers take
them ltd counteract the effects of under
work. "Many great writer to use a
current critical phrase," su's Dr. T. D.
Crothers of Hartford, Conn., "begin the
use of cocaine that they may whip their
Inventiveness to action."
Walters in restaurants use drugs to
quicken their memory. It has been
estimated that 1." per cent, of all the
medical men in the United States are
drug addicts, "One
half of nil my drug
patients ore physi
cians," says Dr.
Towns, who has u
hill now pending at
Albany, Introduced
by Senator John .1.
Itoylan, barring all
drug addicted phy
sicians from prac
tice. School chil
dren, even ut the
ages of 7 and N. are
offered cocnlne nnd
horoln by pedlors
about public school
buildings. The Hull
House campaign of
l'.io.l started with
the disc ivery thai
certain negroes in
Chicago Were stop
ping school chil
dren on the tilde
walks and selling
them a penny Ixoc
of the deadliest
habit forming drug
In the world and
asking them to "tell
all their Hi t I e
friends about It
In that sect Inn
of civilized society
known as the under.
World cocaine ad
diction Is practically
universal Cnderlts
Intluetice ate most of
the daring crimes
committed. Most of
the attacks tiMin
white women of the
South." says Dr
Christopher Koch
"are the tilled re
suit of a cocaine
crazed negro brain
Thousands of dingy
hovels are scattered
tllloliuli ttle negro
sections of Southern
cities where "snow"
is retailed In dime
boxes through back
doors which are
prevented by chains
from opening more
than three Indies
District Attor
ney St. Clair estl
m. les that In New
Orleans nlone there
nie 2.1,000 negro
I calne addicts who
p a t r o n i ze these
I Joints, Overseers of
Southern labor have
been known to put
cocaine Into their
gang's rations in order to get more
work out of them.
As a result of the wide cocaine addic
tion among negroes in the South Au
gust llrahni cites figures to show that
the negro race, which forms lu.T per
cent, of the nation's population, com
mits 37.12 per cent, of the murders.
.1. IMgar llrown of Chicago Is authority
for thij statement that the murder rate
of Germany is three per. he l.'nderwood bill, on October 9. 1913.
made these Incie.ises ever the Payne
tariff: Crude opium Imported for iihiIi
cui.il purposes, l r,o to 43 a pound
di led opium Imported for medicinal pur
poses. (2 to (I a pound; morphine and
Its derivatives, heroin and codeine,
il.."o to 3 an ounce; cocaine, II. ."u to
12 an ounce; coca leaves, 5 cents to 10
i cuts a pound.
The effect of a tariff Increase In abat
ing the Importation t.f these drugs may
lie seen In these tlgllles; The Payne
tariff on August .'i, U'i'9. raised the duty
on cocaine from 2.", per cent, ad valorem
to 11.50 an ounce, and the cocaine Im
port Jumped fr 111 32.272 ounces III 19I
to .H,."i',o ounces In 1910. It took coca
leaves off the free list and Imposed a
duty of a cents a pound, and the coca
iiiiiioit iunniid from 7os.o IC pounds in
1VI0 to 1,2211, 771. .I pounds in 19)1.
once Inside the country the (iovern-i
ment exercises no more supervision
over these deadl habit forming drugs
excepting opium) than over peai k
plumes or frankfurters I
It Is in the New York Legislature
that Mrs. Vandeibll 's nationwide slrug
g'e to exterminate the vice of drug ad
diction I- already opening. Krnest K
Coulter of 2 Hector treet has left in
.he hands of IMvviird .1. Mciioldlick. in
1 charge of New York city legislation at
Albati.v. .Mr-, v.nidorbllt V bill practically
prohibiting the sale of cocaine, helolll
and iiioi pluiie. Senate has not acted on It yet) re
quiring every person who distributes
men leaves to leglster his name with
the colleitor of Internal revenue and to
pay a lax of a dollar a year, further,
prohibiting the selling of cocaine except
on a pun (laser's order to b- kept for two
years, accessible to Federal and State
authorities. Any unregistered person
transporting cocaine fiom State to State
or having It In his itossessbm s made
liable to a 2,0on line or Imprisonment
not to exceed the years, or both.
The same bill furthermore prohibits
the export of opium, raises the Internal
leveiiue tn.x on smoking opium from lia
COCAINE'S DEADLY ACTION.
The itJhttiny erpcricner shova Mr dradtinrB of the iriif uicaw i
rat'ric mldid who the mrdlc often consume Hrentv (train of the dr
thin record the cffict of one grain on a man vho had never tahn ii ljmi
It tea an experiment pcrformid by Dr. Novell Wan, recorded in th, Sull,
cat Xeir" of ISS and widely quoted at that time, ft tra an open qui ti ,nf
doctor then a to whether cocaine wa or wa not dangerous.
At 6 P. M. I injected one-quarter grain of Squlbb's cocaine under the s jn
of my forearm. No result ensuing, the infection was repeated in Mtccn
minutes. At 8:30 P. M general symptoms not having appeared, nclialf
grain was taken, making one grain within half an hour. In tun i mines
systematic effects began: I became restless, respirations 30, shall .w nnj
sighing; pulse 120; had aphasia and increasing precordial oppression
tl 4s now 6:50 P. M. Twenty minutes have elapsed since taking tne lull
grain Iniecllon. My pupil are dilating slowly; mental faculties p rfcu
clear and collected; no pain in head or other part of body; respirations rc.
duced to normal frequency, but very shallow and sighing; pulse Mil. quia,
feeble tand barely perceptible at wrist.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059228/1914-06-03/ed-1/?sp=3&q=cocaine+drug+narcotic+dope+pills+toxic+addict</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Clergyman Declares Cocaine Can BeWis.,,
Bought as Easily as Ice Cream and [.last Saturday.
Asserts That A States Should Have
Uniform LawsTells of Effect of
Drug on Victims.
Hew York."There Is only one way
to pat an end to the cocaine traffic in
the United States, and that is to pass
a comprehensive federal law which
will regulate the sale, net only ef the
harmful and obnoxious cocaine, but all
drugs and narcotics that have vitiat
ing qualities," aafd the Rev. James
B. Curry of St. James' Soman Cotholie
church when asked for his views on
the war on habit forming drugs.
Father Curry became interested in
the fight on cocaine nine years ago, and
he has been fighting it ever since. He
is familiar with every phase of the
matter. No individual state can successfully
combat the evil For mstance. if New
York state passes a drastic law regu- day.
lating the sale of drugs it will be a
-ample matter foe unscrupulous sellers
of the drug to obtain, their supply in
New Jersey or another state.
'On some sides I have heard physi
cians of this city criticised for filling
prescriptions which enable the bearer*
to obtain supplier of cocaine Rput
bie physicians ore striving to lessen
this evil to the best of their ability
"I do think the wholesale drug
houses are responsible for the spread
ef this evil As an example of how
easy it is to obtain cocaine and other
harmful drugs from wholesale bouses,
an acquaintance of mine recently in
formed me that he could jret as much
of the drag as be wanted without an
order from a physician or anybody
ifise I aSBL"* surprised that I re-1
raestet him ttPmafce the effort.
"He made out a list and mailed it to
a drug bouse and asked for prices. In
eluded In the list was cocaine In a
few days he received the list with the
prices filled in, and. checking off some*
of the drugs, including cocaine, he re
mailed the list Not long after that
the goods were delivered, and the co
eaine was in the order. It was as
easy as buying ice cream. 'I saw one of them, sniff cocaine one
day I snt ceeded in obtaining some of
the dni and sent It to the board of
health for analysis, tt was found fa
be 91) TA) per cent cocaine Subsequent
ly the druggist was forced t close up.
'Laws th.it esi* are not comprehen
sive eno'ijili Some new drug springs
up from time To rime and the present
laws do not affect its ^ale-./ I propos*'
that a l.iw be passed that will cover
not onlv the drugs now regulated, but
A. so new drugs that may come into ex
istence A law can be so worded as to
embra the new drugs and there will
be no need for further legislation along
thafhne
Some persons have asked me where
the cocaine habit originally came from.
It is a hard question to answer, hut I
really think that it came from the
West Indies imagine that the negro?
help on ships from the West Indies
brought the habit to New York years
ago."</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058396/1914-06-06/ed-1/?sp=20&q=cocaine+drug+narcotic+dope+pills+toxic+addict</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The greatest drug-using people
In the -world are the American peo
ple and not the Chinese. That Is
the discovert of expert! working
under the direction of Mrs. W. K
Vanderbilt. Sr.. -vho. since January
has been working against the use
of drugs In the United States
Today 4.1 per cent of the Chinese
are drug users in some form. In
America 4.45 per cent cf the popu
lation uses drugs.
Mrs Vanderbilt began her fight
on the nation-wide use of drugs in
the New York Legislature, where
she fought for a bill prohibiting tho
sale of cocaine, heroin and mor
phine. She has given large sums of
money to organizations opposing the
drug habit In her efforts to obtain
legislation against its sale
The entire civilized world has
been shouting about the horrors of
the opium traffic of China. The
Chinese were the originators of
opium. It is believed. In China it
was found 200 years ago that 6
per cent of the people were drug
victims. By consistent fighting
against tho use of drugs; by laws
limiting its manufacture and sale,
the use of druj;s there has dropped
to 4.1 per cent of the population in
200 years.
In America, however; the use of
the drug is on the Increase.
Laws preventing the transporta
tion of cocaine from one State to
another are sought by Mrs. Van
derbilt, and in working for federal
laws her experts have compiled
data to show the enormity of the
drug habit.
Drugs are used by all classes. The
criminal class Is addicted to Its use.
Cocaine 1b Injected Into the aim.
Opium la smoked and taken in oth
er ways. Sometimes the drugs are
snuffed. They are taken to drive
away tho feeling of drowsiness
sometimes. Country doctors ac
quire the drug habit because of
their long hours of work. They
take drugs to keep themselves
awake and take other drugs so they
can go to Bleep quickly.
Society women are known to take
j drugs to drive away weariness in
pursuing their social conquests.
The terrible effects of taking
eocaine have been pointed out time
end again. In 1888 Dr. J. Howell
Way wrote to the Medical News his
experiences with cocaine.
He Bald he Injected, one-quarter
1 grain of cocaine in his forearm at
j 6 p. m. Thirty minutee later he
took a half grain. In ten minutes
he became restless and his hreath
lng was affected. In twenty min
utes his pupils began to dilate.
By 7 20 his condition was near
collapse. By 7:30 he began to fear
he would die. Cocaine was not as
well known then as it is now. and
Dr. Way took the drug simply as
an experiment. Memorial Trade
normal activities In spite of the
drug they take. In America, drug
iis rs quickly lake to cocaine and
heroin. The drug causes the user
to turn criminal and to die. Five
years Is tho average life of tho
cocaine fiend.
No other vice renders its victim
so dangerous. Opium, morphine
and hasheesh -end their victims
searching for solitude, but a sniff of
cocaine. sftfr llftlne its victim into
ITPPER left Mrs. YV. K.
Vanderbilt. Upper
right A victim of the co
caine habit, after receiving
an injection in his arm. Cen
ter Dream of the drug
merchant, getting money
from his victims. Below
Scene in a drug cafe.
a half hour's rosy overestlmatlon.
drops him into the streets and al
les In a state of dangerous mel
ancholia. So brief is the drug's ef
fect that it takes from $4 to $5 a
day to satisfy a cocaine addict.
"Cocaine addiction Is the easiest
habit to acquire and the hardest to
cure." says Dr. Podstata, a Chicago
drug expert. </text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058396/1915-05-22/ed-1/?sp=15&q=cocaine+drug+narcotic+dope+pills+toxic+addict</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Several drug user6 have killed
themselves because of the depriva
tion while others have gone insane
Practically the same results have
been felt in Chicago, St Louis and
other large cities,
j In St. Louis several women have
attempted suicide because they
could not obtain the drugs and in
Chicago a number of crimes have
been tracexi to drug users
The law. many complain, has
placed an absolute ban on the sate
of drugs to those addicted, but it
has made no provision for the cure
of the drug fiends.
In the larger fities the hospitals
established special wards 1
these people might undergo a cure
but the method itself was such a
crude and cruel one that even phy
sicians of repute themselves com
plained. The enforcement of the
law threw thebe new patients on
their hands and they could not treat
them without giving them soma
drugs To break a man or woman
in a day of a habit contracted in
years might cause a fatal reaction
of the heart, they said, and many
of them went on record in opposi
tion to the Harrison la
In several hospitals the Lambert
Townc treatment was used but with
no great success, according to re
ports. It was too severe and Caused
many patients, willing to be cured,
to leave the institution and go back
to their old habits. It was baaed
mostly on hyosciamine a derivative
of opium but left the patient In an
guish for more thai? 48 hours in th
time the new drugs were battling
the habit-forming alkaloids in his
or her system.
The few who underwent this
treatment are said to have returned
to their old haunt.-, and to have ro
newed the use of drugs. In several courts men and worn
en found guilty of selling cocaine
have been given six months in jail,
while under the state laws they re
ceived no more than a 950 fine fr
their offense. The $f.o was paid by
the politician or drug vender and
all was over as far as the courts
were concerned, although the per
son arrested man or woman prat
beaten almost into Insensibility bj
the drug-vender and other friends
when he or she returned to the
colony.
The terrible stream under Whli h
these people live where they al
most worship the one man who can
supply them with drugs and are
cruelly beaten by him when they
are caught by private investigators
has been revealed to Federal in
vestigators in recent raids. In fact,
II Is ibe intention of the United
States government to go more deep
ly intc these matters and ferret out
nol the poor unfortunates Who sell
cocaine for commission of the
drug itself, but the real persona
who make ihe profit.
The Federal courts are nirl. Qg
out Jail sentences to the small of
fenders, but when the internal rev
enue agents get to the real sellers
of cocaine the men who make a
great profit from the misfortunes of
their brothers there will be sen
tences of not less than five years
in the Federal penitentiary, It is
said.
The smaller offenders are the men
and women who sell the dine lor
their master, the man in control of
ihe supply, for a commission on
drugs. They work and slave for
him and he owns them body and
soul by his payment of a small box
of cocaine or a few morphine tab
lets. The man In control Is all the
more heartless In that he is not a
user of the drugs himself, (such a
man might be in sympathy with oth
er stricken creatures) but is wise
enough to let it alone and profit by
their experiences.
In a recent raid of opium joints
and lairs of the users of morphine
and cocaine. Col. L. G N'utt. in
Charge of the eastern division of
Missouri and one of the most effl-
A TYPICAL. ALLELE WHERE "DOPC FIEND5" THRIVE.. I
cient and experienced internal rev
enue agents in the country, found
hundreds of unfortunates under the
influence of drugs.
A SK
j i'min r.
In St. Louis his men under h's dl-
rection arrested Henry Wilsmatf
the so-called "Cocaine King." This
man. kuown as "Wig Henry. and
having served a penitentiary sen
tence for slaying "Red" Tremalne,
the laBt "cocaine king," is alleged to
have been selling the drugs to a
colony of cocaine and morphine
users in a miserable row of tene
ments nearby a structure known as
Filipino Row, and so filthy and foul
that no human being, unless under
the Influence of drugs, would live
there
There were men and women of all
types found there. Sturdy men who
worked hard in the daytime so that
in the night they might supply them
selves with drugs, and women who
Hacrificed everything so that they,
too might satisfy Hiis craving. There
were women still showing marks of
refinement women who in their
day had been of more or less boi ial
prominence in the city. One wom
an in particular was Doted for her
utter degradation She is a member
of a prominent family. She ip
wealthy, and owns a row of build
ings valued at about $100,000. She
rents these buildings to drug users
and from the high rents she charges,
more than derives enough money to
well supply b 1 11 If if h the drug
she craves.
While living another life she
might be prominent socially and
financially, but now she is known as
the "snow bird." She lives in a
basement hovel of one of h'i own
buildings and Is in fear of ihe death
that she knows the cocaine-nends
will metS out to her some day. She
has money and she thinks that some
night some maddened drug user will
rome to her miserable dwelling ana
murder her for her money.
In all of he misery and filth that
surround her, she is not more mis
erable ihan the unfortunates who
pay hf r for the renl of their squalid
one-room dwellings, and pay glnd
ly so that thev may be near their
source of supply of the orugs.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1914-03-01/ed-1/?sp=14&q=cocaine+in+america&st=text&r=-0.237,-0.074,1.475,1.475,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>On some sides I have heard physicians
of this city criticised for filling prescrip
tions which enable the bearers to obtain
supplies of cocaine, Reputablo physicians
ure striving to lessen this evil to tho brst
of their ability.
I"n to Ray Cocaine.
"I do think the wholsale drug houses
are responsible for the spread of tals evil.
As an example of how easy It Is to obtain
cocaine and other harmful drugs from
wholerulo houses, 1111 acquaintance of mine
recently Informed me that he could get
as much of the drug as he wanted with
out an order from a physician or anybody
rise. 1 was so surprised that I requested
him to make thn effort.
"He made out a list and mailed It to
a drug house and asked for prices. In
cluded In tho llrt was cocaine. In a
few days he received the, list with the
prices filled in and checking off rome
of the drugs. Including cocaine, he re
nal!cd the list. Not long after that the
goods were delivered and the cocaine
was in the order. It was as easy as buy
ing Ice cream.
"It was in 190S that I first took up
the cudgels against the sellers of cocaine.
I noticed rallors drifting over rrom tho
Bowery nnd patronizing a certain drug
gist, Before entering the store thee men
seemed to be downhearted and despond
ent, but coming nut their manner had
undergone a change. They appeared fo
be animated and gleeful, cut up capers
and seemed pleased with everything In
general.
Sees Man Use Trnsr,
"I saw one of them sniff cocaine one
day. I succeeded In obtaining some of
the drug und sent It to the Board of
Health for analysis. It was found to be
cocaine 99,60 per cent, cocaine, flubse
.uently the druggist wus forced to close
up.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075258/1949-01-12/ed-1/?sp=12&q=cocaine+in+america&st=text&r=-0.243,-0.074,1.485,1.485,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86074053/1909-10-21/ed-1/?sp=1&q=cocaine+in+america&st=text&r=-0.338,-0.173,1.587,1.587,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86074011/1910-05-06/ed-1/?sp=5&q=cocaine+in+america&st=text&r=-0.155,-0.026,1.309,1.309,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>On the contrary, the morphine habit
is distinct and is usually acquired without any
preliminary "pipe" experience, but the road from
opium to morphine Is open and easy.
Cocaine on the contrary, bears no relation to
opium. It Is not a derivative; it gives entirely
different sensations: and it is a separate and dis
tinct habit. It is allied to opium only in this:
the morphine victim occasionally turns to cocaine
for relief when trying to break himself of the
morphine habit, and, according to the Chicago io
lice, there are occasional "fiends" so far gone
that they use both, finding that one so counteracts
the other In its physical effects that it is possible
to use more of each without danger. So. while
cocaine itself bears no relation to opium, there is
an occasional connection between the cocaine
habit and the morphine habit, and the confusion
that makes it necessary to include cocaine in a
discussion of opium and its derivatives is not al
together without justification.
It is a common belief that desperate criminals
are generally, or at least often, "dope fiends."
When the perpetrator of a particularly daring
crime is caught, It is not unusual to find the news
papers gravely announcing that he is a victim of
the cocaine habit. It may be morphine, or it may
be just "dope" generally, but It is usually cocaine.
The more sensational the crime or series of
crimes for which a man or a gang Is responsible,
the more certain we are to learn that "dope" had
much to do with the making of the criminal or
criminals. It takes such a hold on a man, we
are told, that he will commit any crime to obtain
It. Peing In need of his cocaine or his morphine
opium itself has not such a bad name in this
way we picture him taking his magazine pistol
and going out to get the necessary money.
I asked a Chicago policeman of much experi
ence about this.
"If a dope fiend needed his dope." he said, "and
had a magazine pun or any other kind of a gun,
he'd hock the gun."</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84036012/1893-10-24/ed-1/?sp=6&q=cocaine+in+america&st=text&r=-0.289,-0.014,1.579,1.579,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>STORYOF A COCAINE VICTIM.^Taken First to Kellsve N.rvoosasss, II^^om Beeaana His Creel Master.
Itwaa in l**89 that I received my first^doae of cocaine, says a writer in the New^^ark Caff. Being engaged iu work that^placed a heavy strsln on the mental pow^^ers, an extremely nervous condition and^incapacity for duty were soon brought^about. A physician during one of these^attacks suggested be could relieve it. A^call was made at his office and a solution^then unknown lo me was sprinkled into my^head through tho nostrils. The effect was^both magical and instantaneous. All pain^and nervousness disappeared, and for^hours I worked without the slightest feel^^ing of fatigue. But the reaction soon came^and 1 was worse than before using tha^medicine. Having free access to the doc^^tor's office, 1 again used the drug as I had^aeen him do, and so secured the desired^effect, unaware of its harmful properties.^My work increased, and in order to ac^^complish all I desired to do I repeated the^visits whenever I felt tired. My appear^^ance so. .n denoted to the physician's prac^^ticed eye that something was wrong and^he accused me of using cocaine. Pointing^to tho bottle on the stand, I saidt
That is all I have used.
MyCod. man!^ the doctor exclaimed,^^quit using that stuff; it is cocaine and^will kill you.
Ireadily promised what be desired, and^went about my business, congratulating^myself on my fortunate escape. Soon the^old foiling came over ma, and thinking,^like many others, that I could stop when^I felt like it, I secured a small quantity of^the drug, to use as a bracer, aa I assured^my self. As the drug saturated my system^the pleasant dreams I at first experienced^ceased. They were succeeded by the most^horrible nightmares. My sense of hearing^became intensely acuta. The slightest^sound was magnified a hundred fold. I^would start up in bed terror-stricken. Im^^agining someone was In the room. The^idea that someone was watching ma was^constantly with me. I placed putty in tha^keyhole and stopped up all the cracks in^my bedroom door with paper. On tha^street I would stop and look at people^walking behind, under the dsluslon that^they were following me.
Thatwas the commencement of the^trouble. I began to like cocaine and re^^sorted to its use on the slightest pretext.^At last I decided to break off, whan to my^horror, I discovered that I was no longer^my own master. I must have cocaine or^suffer the worst kind of torture, and I^gave in. In six months' time I was^reduced from a hale and vigorous man^to a perfect wreck, both physically and^mentally. I was totally unfitted for^business, shunned my friends and old^associates, in fact, became a pariah and^outcast from all respectable society. As^the habit grew, the demand for cocaine be^^came more frequent. These illusions could^only be dispelled by its use, and the effect^of a dose would not last more than an^hour, in some instances only lf^ minutes.^1 have been on a street car when the crav^^ing came over me so strongly that I was^obliged to got off the car and go Into some^saloon to use my syringe and secure re^^lief. During all this time I imagined that^no one but myself knew of my habit.^This is one of the effects of the drug.^With my eyes diatended and glaring, my^bps, ears, face and hand* fairly black^from ita use, I would indignantly deny to^my best frieuds last I was using any^drug.
Ihad been on a 10-day spree, using on^an average 100 grains of cocaine a day.^When I returned home t was ^loaded to^the guards,^ aud still had plenty of the^stuff with me. My people locked ma in a^room and took all the cocaine away. Soon^the agony began. There was a large^screen near my bod, over tho top of which^I saw tho face of a man, who seemed to^be imitating my actions when taking co^^caine. I could hear people talking^outside my door. I took the coun^^terpane from the bed and hung it^from the top of the door to keep them^from seeing me. lists soon began^to get iu the bed clothing, and that was^consigned to the floor. My prayers and^imprecations for cocaine were denied by^my folks and the agony increased. At^last I imagined some one waa blowing^chloroform through the keyhole of (he^door. 1 began to choke and amother, and,^with a scream, fell back on the lied, to^awake tlm next day on a rot in a hospital,^having been unconscious for several^hours.
Suchare a few of he many experiences^I passed through, and my advice to the^reador ia, shun cocaine aa you would a^coal of lire. There la only one result from^lie use broken health, poverty and tho^poiter'a held.
i. ui.in'i Stead Vanishment.</text>
      </result>
    </results>


  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-spanish-flu</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058396/1918-05-08/ed-1/?sp=4&q=epidemic+EPIDEMIC</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89064695/1918-06-27/ed-1/?sp=2&q=pneumonia+epidemic&r=-0.334,0.118,1.129,0.633,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1918-07-11/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Europe+influenza+germ+Influenza+Spanish+Germ&st=text&r=-0.162,-0.049,1.325,1.325,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Please send some of your
scientists to study that Spanish
Influenza, its causes, the possibility
of fighting It, and especially of
keeping it out of the United States.
It Is known that John D. Rocke
feller's Idea, which controls his
son in the use of the Rockefeller
fortune. Is to spend money FOR
PREVENTION rather than for the
cure of individual cases. Not to
cure one or a thousand sick peo
ple, but to find a way to prevent
millions in future from catching
disease that Is the Rockefeller
idea.
Investigation of this strange dis
ease In Europe, sending some of
the Rockefeller scientists, gather
ed from all over the world, Japan,
France and elsewhere, would be a
step in the line of prevention.
Later, having identified the
germ, probably one of those little
things that look like a colled
spring, now circulating rapidly In
the Kaiser's blood, Mr. Rockefeller
might put up a small monument to
It with this label, "Germ of the
Spanish influenza disease, much
enlarged. This monument built
Br a grateful Rockefeller, to the
germ that made the Kaiser tired
or irar.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1918-09-20/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Influenza+Service+Pfelffer+Spanish+flu+influenza+Health+SPANISH+Public&st=text&r=-0.182,-0.068,1.364,1.364,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The germ of Spanlph Influenza Jias
fcecn Isolated and Identified as the Pfelf
fer1 bacillus, the cause of the old form
of grip, thus giving the medical pro-
fesslon absolute knowledge for'lts fight J
against' the disease,, which Is assuming
aspects' of 'an epidemic in this city.
Proof" of the germ's Identity was
established by Pf. Paul A. Lewis, di
rector of the laboratories at Phipps In
stltute. Seventh and lximbard streets.
Jt Is believed to 'be the first successful
dentlflcatlon of the bacillus In the
tlnited States, i 'sl
Doctor Lewis' Identification of the
'Spanish 'Infiuehra germ was the result
pf laborious tests made- from a number
jot cultures. The Pfelffer germ was
named after nlchard Pfelffer, ft former
German army surgeon, who, in 1892, j
'dlsc'overed the germ of Influensa.
w The Isolation of the Influenza germ
was, the. outstanding feature In the
Spanish grip situation here today.
Other features of the situation are:
Local health officials have caffed a
conference tomorrow- to consider making i
ihe dttease reportable. Medical and housing authorities this
afternoon pointed out the posslbili'y of
Spanish Influenza btcomlng epidemic in
Philadelphia because of the serious over
crowding whic exists
They say, however, there is. no present
cause for alarm, despUe the .thousand
cases among men In the navy now In
this city and the many cases reported
lri "the civilian population, ordinary
precaution will prevent an epidemic. It is
declared.
But tens .of thousands of war Work
err added tn, city'" normal popu
lation' have placed houses at a premium,
and hftve packed dwellings with ship
and '-munition .workers. Overcrowded
street .ears, physicians' point out, are
also "seed beds" for the "flu."
'Several, wards at the Municipal Hos
pital for "Contagious Diseases, Second
and 'Luzerne Streets, have been turned
vr to the naval authorities to help
4 pj-event. a spread of Influenza among
A. sailors .ana murines w m
i'HNavy Yard.
T TTortram Mitchell' of Wayne, n
jS'promlnent business man of this city, and
three sailors nae unm iic .o..
cf Influenza.
'Another Philadelphlan. Lieutenant
Albert Charles noberts. u. s. N.,'or 2411
North Fifty-sixth street, Wynnefleld, is
i Head ttt an Atlantic port, OI innueiiia.
rt.i u.-i.T .Harriann. flrst-class fireman.
Il2?i a
11m wKT state street. Ban irancisco, oieo iu
I'jjW; ii, viOni TlnsnltHl from nneu
l;jf. monia. following an attack of influenza </text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1918-09-21/ed-1/?sp=1&q=case+influenza+INFLUENZA+PLAGUE+Spanish+quarantine&r=-0.671,-0.047,2.342,1.312,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NFLUENZA CLAIMS
VICTIM IN CAPITAL
Outbreak of "Spanish" influenza
among Washington's civilian popula
tion was revealed today when the
first fatal case had been reported to
the District Health Office. Every
precaution has been taken to prevent
a spread of the malady, and warning
Is given against undue alarm.
The first District man to succumb
to the disease Is John W. Clore,
twenty-four years old, of 1103 -Florida
avenue northeast. No additional
cases have been reported.
Clore Is believed to have contract
ed the malady while visiting In New
York. He returned from a week's
vacation In that city Tuee:v, and
resumed his Vork as a freight brake
mane on the Pennsylvania lullroad.
He was very 111 on Thursday and he
remained at home.
Dies at Hospital.
The patient was taken to Sibley
Hospital last night. He died early
this morning. District Health Offi
cer Powler stated that establish
ment of quarantine at Clore'a home
waa not necessary.
rtnM hail Kn r.tiif.nt of Wash
ington for twelve years, coming here
from Culpeper, Va. He Is survived
by a daughter, Margaret Clore; his
r- -MV T. "41. Clore. of
Culpeper, Va.; a. sister, Mrs. Margar
et J. Verherst. ana a nrotner, i nomas
Clore.
TK.AMnv ft wm fh. inlth rtffiee vla-
Ited Lieut, and Mrs. Arthur Henne. of
13C3 Eighteenth street northwest, res-
T4a Mnnl. .ttt-n,wf frnm Tew
York Monday and manifested symp
toms of tbo malady.
Laboratory Tests.
Examination failed to establish a
positive diagnosis, according to Dr.
Fowler. Laboratory tests are being
made today to clear up any doubts as
to the presence of the causative s-rm-The
positive identification of the -g- .n
by Philadelphia scientists will aid Ly
txiet officials In their campalm to
combat the ailment.
Medical corps men believed they had
the epidemic at Camp Humphreys un
der control today. Twelve cases were
reported among the soldiers.
Dr. Fowler bad advised Washington
residents who suspect symptoms of the
TE Dr. William C. Fowler, District
Health Officer, asks all Washing
ton physicians to report to him
eases which they suspect to be
"Spanish" laSnenaa.
There Is no cause fr alarm be
cause at the presence of the dis
ease In the District, but prampt
precautions ahonld be taken In
suspected eases to prevent spread
ot the malady.
disease to order the Immediate ls-.li-tlon
of the patient. The ailment can
be cured by careful treatment.
PLAGUE IN CHICAGO
CHICAGO, Sept. 51. Spanish in
fluenza has Invaded Chicago, and
army training students at Lewis In
stitute, In consequence, are now un
der quarantine. It Is believed the
epidemic here was started by the
mingling of some of the men at so
cial functions which Great Lakes
Jackles attended.
At Lake Forest College and North
western University more than 100
girl victims are reported. There are
sixty cases reported at ForteSheridan,
and Wilmette, a north share suburb,
reports fifty.
Army, Federal, and local authori
ties are co-operating In the Sight
against the malady.
QUApjTM;ATi)AftJP
-ATfxANTA. QHyBeptZfSL As-he
result of an epidemic of Spanish In
fluenza throush''entIf regiments of
Infantry, six In. CampGordon and a
number of smaller organizations are
In quarantine today.
Camp medical officer, are taking
every precaution to prevent the
spread of the malady. V
While no definite information Is at
hand. It is stated that the number of
new cases of the disease are increas
ing.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88084272/1918-09-27/ed-1/?sp=1&q=case+INFLUENZA+influenza+Influenza+plague+Spanish</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Spanish influenza, sweeping
through all but 1 of the army camps
and apparently beyond control in
many eastern communities, has caused
a tremendous increase In the death
rate of the army at home.
For the week ending Septem
ber 20. the surgeon general's of
fice reported today, the death
rate was 4.4 per cent, compared
with 23 per cent the preceding
week.
This Increase was attributed in
large measures to influenza, but the
report pointed out that the figures
do not show the seriousness of the
situation as since last Friday there
has been a farther rapid spread of
the epidemic with many deaths.
The surgeon general's office
said the epidemic may be expect
ed to sweep westward with a still
greater Increase In mortality In
the next few weeks.'
Orders issued last night by pro
vost marshal general Crowder can
celling calls for entrapment of 142,
00 draft registrants between October
7 and 11 were due to the serious con
ditions in many camps and were said
by health officials to be absolutely
necessary at this time.
Boston Needs 500 Doctors.
Boston. Maas.. Sept. 27. Health au
thorities in Massachusetts, who have
been battling unceasingly to check
the spread of Influenza, were today
hoping for the arrival of physicians I
.ana narses ma onisioe tne scan, in
Toapoain tar uraaw. aapseis Bjr tae
dovernor. Dr. Eugene R. Kelley. state
health commissioner, estimated that
5 so physicians and 1000 nurses were
needed. Traveling expenses and sal
ary will be paid all who respond.
Public Meetings Banned.
Beginning today, all public meet
ings in this city were to be prohibit
ed, aa far as practicable bv the emer
gency health commission. It bas left
optional with the churches as to
whether services should be held next
Sunday.
Tbe cessation or a heavy rain,
whlcji fell for 36 hours, and the re
turn of sunshine were looked upon as
sugaring well for the fight against
the epidemic.
Influenza In Denver.
Denver. Colo, Sept. 17. The first
case of Spanish Influenza reported in
Denver became known today with the
death of Miss Blanche Kennedy, of
Chicago. She came here last Saturday
to visit a brother. No other eases
have been reported to the health</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1918-10-06/ed-1/?sp=22&q=influenza+Boston+Influenza+military</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE first really serious epidemic of
disease produced by the great war
is that called "the Bpaniah Influ
enza" which has caused deplorable mor
tality In New York and New England.
At the outset It should be said that the
term "Spanish infiuenxa" Is clearly an
error, and that the name should be "Ger
man Influenza," for Investigation proves
that the disease originated In the German
trenches. It has since made a tour ot the
entire civilized world, In the course ot
which It broke out with especial severity
in Spain, owing to certain local conditions.
The French, noting Its ravages in Spain,
and not having suffered very badly them
selves, gave It the title "Spanish Influ-
ua"
That this should be the only epidemic
disease produced by the world war Is a
remarkable proof of the protection afforded
to ns. by modern medicine and hygiene.
After nearly all other great wars, as a re
sult ot the misery, starvation and enfeeble
ment of the population, there have been
great outbreaks of pestilence, which have
depopulated cities and even countries.
The disease generally known as "the
bubonic plague" is the great plague which
caused the great ravages of past war
epochs, its cost in human lives has not
been less than two billions. In addition, out
breaks of smallpox, cholera, typhus and
yellow fever have followed debilitating
wars.
Fortunately our enormous progress in
medicine and our material resources for
combating disease give assurance that no
plague epidemic of such magnitude as
those ot the past can orcur in America at
the present time.
How widespread has been the outbreak
of Spanish Influenza Is shown by the fact
that our Assistant Secretary of the Navy,
Franklin D. Roosevelt, suffered from it,
while, at about the time he was recovering
the youngest son of the King of Sweden
died of it.
The first known advent of the influenza
In this country occurred when the Nor
wegian ship Bergensfjord arrived at New
York on August 12 with twenty-five cases,
three ot whom died, but there were prob
ably other sources of infection, apart from
the report that the German U-boats sur
reptitiously disseminated the Infection in
this country. Independent sources of in
fection, apparently, reached Boston and
New England, where the disease raged
most alarmingly, causing seventy deaths
in one day and 9.000 cases at the Camp
Devens military camp.
And now just what happens to the suf
ferer from Spanish Influenza? From obser
vations ot one thousand soldiers It was
found that from one to three days after
contact or approach to others who had Ibo
disease a feverish state began This fever
rose steadily until on the second or third
day afterwards, it was as high as occurs
in pneumonia. In many cases it went as
high at 104 deg. Fahr. Indeed, it is ap
parent that one of the most common as
well as the most dangerous complications
is that ot pneumonia.
The disease starts with a chill or chills
that may shake the whole room you're in
Severe headaches, with pains in the legs,
In the groin. In the neck, in the spine, and
in the small of the back are generally
present
Then "that tired feeling." named by doc
tors "general malaise," takes charge of the
safferer'a anatomy The Ictlm feels
wretched all over Fever blisters, those
frequent accompaniments of pneumonia, of
meningitis and of tertian malaria, "break
jut" on the sufferer's lips.
The face becomes flushed, a thermom
eter stuck under the tongue registers 102
to 104 degroes. and the victim as well as
his doctors knows he's in for it badly.
Spanish influenza "cures or kills" in
Liberty motor speed. Within four days the
worst Is usually over. About the second
day the abrupt crisis takes place. On the
fourth day the patient is either as well as
he ever was, or pneumonia or another com
plication asserts its dangerous presence.
A harsh cough is a frequently encountered
2 ft
Hirshberg', A. M., M. D.
symptom. The patient thus hacks and
sprays forth lots of the microbes, which
spread the infection rapidly unlcBs handlod
with the greatest precaution.
A thick, tenacious sputum of a whitish
mucoid character distinguishes this new
disease from the well-known old influenza
with its greenish sputum. This also dis
tinguishes Spanish Influenza from pneumo
nia, with Its typical "rusty colored tough
expectoration."
Failure of Intestinal action, a restricted
flow of the kidney fluids and a want of
appetite rlay a large role In the charac
teristic signs and symptoms ot Spanish
Influenza.
If you take close notice of the several
differences between this new malady and
the old influenza, you will observe that the
fever Is sharper, higher, but of shorter
duration; the total course of the new
scourge Is briefer; thero are fewer stomach
or intestinal Bymptoms in the Spanish
influenza, whereas in the previously known
influenza gastro-Intestinal disturbances
were predominant.
A most important discovery has just
been made nith regard to this disease
The specific microbe which causes It has
been definitely isolated. This is a complete
disproof of the assertion In some medical
publications that the bacillus was the
same as that of the old influenza, or grip.
This Interesting discovery Is due to the
researches of three English army sur
geons. Captains T. R. Little, C. J. Garafalo
and P. A. Williams, ot the Canadian Mo
bile Bacteriological Laboratory, attached
to the British base hospitals.
The last great pandemic of grip, or in
fluenza, lasted threo years, from 1889 until
1892. It spread like wildfire over the
civilized world during that period. Then
several American bacteriologists at work
simultaneously and Professor Pfeiffer dis
covered the grip germ, or influenza bacil
lus, which has since been confirmed and
established as the specific cause of the
colds, pains, backaches and other classical
symptoms of the old-time grip.
The present scourge, it was soon found,
is much more malignant and entirely dif
ferent from the other
The manner in which the bacterial agent
which causes this plague was run to earth
is a model of the bacteriological skill, su
premacy, efficiency and patience of the
English and American medical staffs.
It was recognized that the rapidity with
which the contagion spread pretty well
pointed to some microbe or bacterium as
the guilty party. It was also argued that
the causative agent must lurk at least a
large part of the time in or near the air
passages of the victim.
The coughs, the sputum tho pneumonia
and bronchitis complications, the spray
from the nose and throat as it came in
direct contact with the men or reached
them through plates, dishes and linens,
seemed to Invito bacteriological searches
and microscopic studies
Fortunately, for all of us on thlb side of
the ocean, medical science has mcceeded in
Isolating and Identifying the germs in just
that way at the very beginning of the
American epidemic, which is thereforo like
ly to be nipped in the bud.
The new bacillus is not in tho blood.
Cultivation ot It Is impossible from this
source It Is lucky that so demoniacal a
bug does not penetrate thf delicate fluid
tissue of man. Then Its malignancy
would perhaps be tenfold.
However, when the bacteriologists ex
plored the discharges and excretions from
the nose, the pharynx and the throat, lo
nnd behold! their pioneer work was at
last rewarded.
Spread upon glass and examined under
a magnification of 1,200 times, a new
microscopic living world opened up before
their astonished gaze
A veritable beehive of trembling, vibrat
ing bacilli almost as round and as small
and resembling tho dlplococcus of menlngi
lis loomed up beneath tho high magnlflca
tions of the microscope. A dlplococcus is
a type of microbe In which two disc-like
hhapes are attached to one another.
At the poles or opposing ends of this
myriad of tiny germs their torpedo, blunt
noses were flattened out to make them al
most biscuit shaped.
How the First Real Epidemic of
the World War Spread from
the German Trenches and Why
Science Believes It Has Averted
Si,viU
Mulct Snch as This Are Being Wore by
Sufferer In the Camps and by all Thote
Who Coma In Contact with Them, Thai
Entirely Doing Away with Danger
of Communicating the Infection.
In no "smears" of these bacteria were
there any ot the well-known Pfeiffer bacilli
of influenza or any double cocci ot pneu
monia. The newly discovered germ has charac
teristics peculiarly Its own. These are de
scribed in technical reports In the London
Lancet for July and the British Medical
Journal tor August 10, 1918.
As a rule there are so many bacteria that
are superficially at first glance exactly
alike that a mere Inspection nf them un
dyed or unstained under the microscope
without planting them In various small test
tubes of different soils would fool even ex
perts into believing that they are similar
and Identifiable. Tbat the influenza germs have been se
cretly scattered in this country by German
U-boats is a charge difficult to prove, but
their gas attacks on crows of our light
ships and lighthouses furnish character
evidence against them.  It
then broke out in Spain, and as the French
civilians first noticed its ravages there
they called it Spanish influenza. It Is sig
nificant that Intercourse between Germany
and Spain by U-boat and in other ways
has been particularly frequent From
these two centres its world-wide, spread
has started.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062055/1918-10-11/ed-1/?sp=1&q=influenza+Influenza+Service+SERVICE+Spanish+FLU+Public+INFLUENZA+HEALTH+SPANISH+Health+PUBLIC+publication</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>"SPANISH INFLUENZA,"
"THREE-DAY FEVER,"
AND '"THE FLU"
History of This Disease and Va
rious Symptoms Which May
Be Noted.
UNITED STATES PUBLIC HEALTH
SERVICE,
Rupert Blue, Surgeon General.
What is Spanish Influenza? Is it
something new? Does it come from
Spain?
The disease now occurring in this
country and called "Spanish Influ
enza" resembles a very contagious
kind of "cold" accompanied by fever,
pains in the head, eyes, ears, back or
other parts of the body, and a feeling
of severe sickness. In most of the
cases the symptoms disappear after
three or -four days the patient then
rapidly recovering; some of the pa
tients, however, develop pneumonia, or
inflammation of the ear, or menin
gitis, and many of these complicated
cases die. Whether this so-called
"Spanish" influenza is identical with
the epidemics of influenza of earlier,
years is not yet known.
Epidemics of influenza have visited
this country since 1647. It is interest
ing to know that this first epidemic
was brought here from Valencia,
Spain. Since that time there have
been numerous epidemics of the dis
ease. In 1889 and 1890 an epidemic
of influenza, starting somewhere in
the Orient, spread first to Russia, and
thence over practically the entire civ
ilized world. Three years later there
was anothr flare-up of the disease.
Both times the epidemic spread widely
over the United States.
Although the present epidemic Is
called "Spanish influenza" there is no
reason to believe that it originated in
Spain. Some writers who have stud
ied the question believe that the epi
demic came from the Orient and they
call attention to the fact that the Ger
mans mention the disease as occurring
along the eastern front in he summer
and fall of 1917.
How Can "Spanish Influenza" Be Rec
ognized? There is as yet no certain way in
which a single case of "Spanish in
fluenza" can be recognized on the
other hand, recognition is easy where
there is a group of cases. In contrast
to the outbreaks of ordinary coughs
and colds, which usually occur in thej
cold months, epidemics" or mnuonza
may occur at any season of the year,
thus the present epidemic raged most
intensely in Europe in May, June, and
July. Moreover, in the case of ordi
nary colds, the .general symptoms
(fever, pain depression) are by no
means as severe or as sudden in their
onset as they are influenza. Finally,
ordinary colds do not spread through
the community so rapidly or so exten
sively as does influenza.
In most cases a person taken sick
with influenza feels sick rather sud
denly. He feels weak, has pains in
the eyes, ears, head or back, and may
bo sore all over. Many patients feel
dizzy, some vomit. Most of the pa
tients complain of feeling chilly, and Prof. Edick Passes Away.
P,rof. R. O. Edick, head of the train
ing department of the Normal school,
died Wednesday following an attack
of influenza with other complications.
Prof. Edick recently came to Flagstaff
with his family from the southern
part of the state to take the position
at the Normal.
The remains were taken to the Ari
zona Undertaking Parlors and pre
pared for shipment to his old home in
Wisconsin on No. 8 yesterday morn
ing. Prof. Edick leaves a1 wife and three
children.
EPIDEMIC OF "FLU"
NOT ALARMING HERE
"Conditions in Flagstaff are
not alarming and there are very
few cases of sickness that are se-
rious," Is the statement of Coun-
ty Health Officer Wilson.
"There is nothing to be alarm-
eu about, for wo nave the best
climate in the world to withstand
the influenza as well as most
other diseases. The epidemic here
is in a mild form and all it needs
is reasonably good treatment to
prevent any serious results.
merely because every precaution
has been taken to prevent as
much suffering as possible,
should not alarm the people.
This epidemic, like all others,
will spend its force in a short
time and all that is beinir done is
to brine about that end as
quickly as possible."
"Observe the simple rules of
health, stay away from public
places as much as possible, thus
contribute to public welfare."</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99063812/1918-11-07/ed-1/?sp=1&q=influenza+INFLUENZA+masks+Spanish&r=-0.752,-0.029,2.504,1.403,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085488/1918-11-15/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Influenza+quarantine+influenza+Quarantine+Spanish</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88064305/1918-10-03/ed-1/?sp=1&q=spanish+influenza&st=text&r=-0.435,-0.094,1.871,1.871,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Givernment agencies planned
to help local communities combat
the Spanish influenza.
Telegrams from Washington
greatly reassured local cotton
men as to goverment price fixing.
General Allenby's Palestine suc
cess was declared to prove anew
the disaster of German domination
The minimum of the fourth Lib
erty Loan was put at $6,000,000,
000, the bonds to run twenty
years and bear 4-4 per cent inter
est.
Spanish influenza appeared at
Camp Beauregard. Many new
cases and a number of deaths at
the army and navy camps.
Hard fighting was reported on
the Franco-American front in
Champagne and northwest of
Verdun.
British army in Palestine cap
tured 42,000 Turks in its last
great offensive and continued to
advance.
French and American troops
launched an assault on a forty
mile front and captured 5000
prisoners and many guns.
The demoralized retreat of the
Germans and Bulgarians in Mace
donia continued.
The Spanish influenza epidemic
caused the cancellation of orders
for the entrainment of 142,000
draft registrants.
Senator Ransdell asserted
granting of suffrage to negro
women would alter the political
situation in the South.
Herman Moyse of Baton Rouge
was given high praise and disting
uished service cross by General
Pershiug.
Registrants who desire to quali
fy for 'r-vice were told minor de
fects will b treated by the govern.
ment free of charge.
Give un your luxuries that tliB
K-,iUse-r may be made to give up
hip ambitions.
The British captured the Bul
garian stronghold. Strumnitzr,
and the Serbs took Kochana.
Bulgaria asked an armistice for
forty.eight hours, which was re
fused by officers at the front pend
ing instructions.
In his Liberty Loan speech in
New York President Wilson de
clared there could be no peace
by bargain or compromise.
Spanish influenza continued to
spread in army camps, 6824 new
eases being reported.
A fleet of barges is now started
from St. LI us to New Orleans,
under the g :vernment plan fr a
reaewal of ..'er transportation.
A service flag containing 167,-.
000 stars was presented to the
United Confederate Veterans as
their reunion opened in Tulsa,
Okla.
American troops from New
York, Tennessee and the Caro
linas were a part of Haig's army
that stormed and carried three
miles of the Hindenburg line.
The battleship Minnesota struck
a mine off the Delaware Break
water, but there weie no casual
ties anrid the vessel returned to
port under her own power.
The Allies in the past week
made advances on all fronts and
took 150,000 prisoners and 900
guns.
Bulgary's insistance on the
disposition of territorial question
at the final peace conference was
the only bar to an armistice.
American high explosive shells
from big guns were reported caus.
ing fires far behind the German
lines.
Heavy increases in the number
of new cases of influenza and in
deaths from pnenmonia in army
cautonments were reported.
A rigid quarantine was inau.
gurated between Camp Beaure
gard and Alexandria on account
of an influenza epidemic.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>1</id>
	<rel>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88064328/1918-10-12/ed-1/?sp=6&q=spanish+influenza&st=text&r=-0.295,-0.079,1.589,1.589,0</rel>
	<text>SPANISH INFLUENZA
THREE DAY FEVER.
We were handed the subjoined
article on "Spanish Influenza by
dity riivsician Dr. W. F. Carstens
and requested to reproduce it:
"What is Spanish Inuuenaa? Is
jt something new? Docs it come
from Spain T
The disease now occurring in
this country and called "Spanish
Influenza" resembles a very con
tagious kind of "cold accompan
ied by fever, pains in the head,
eves, ears, back or other parts of
the body, and a feeling of severe
sickness. In most of the cases the
Symptoms disappear after three
or four days, the patient then rap
idly recovering; some of the
patients, however, develop pneu
monia. or inflammation of the ear.
or meningitis, and many of
Whether
complicated eases die
this so-called "Spanish" influen
ça is identical with the epidemics
of influenza of earlier years is not
yet known.
Epidemics of influenza have
visited this country since 647. It
is interesting to know that this
first epidemic was brought here
from Valencia, Spain. Since that
lime there have been numerous
epidemics of the disease. In 1889
and 1800 an epidemic of influ
enza, starting somewhere in the
Orient, spread first, to Russia, and
thence over practically the entire
civilized world. Three years later
there was another flare-up of the
disease. Both times the epidemic
spread widely over the United
Ötfttos. i-* u
Although the present epidemic is
called "Spanish influenza," there
ia no reason to believe that it
orignated in Spain. Some writers
'irtio have studied the question be
lieve that the epidemic came
from the Orient and they call at
Jtention to the fact that the Ger
mans mention the disease as oc
curring along the eastern front in
the summer and fall of 1917.
How can "Spanish influenza
lie recognized T
There is as yet no certain way
in which a single case of "Spanish
influenza" can be recognized; on
the other hand, recognition is easy
where there is a group of cases. In
contrast to the outbreaks of ordi
nary coughs and colds. which
usually occur in the cold months,
epidemics of influenza may occur
at any season of the year, thus
the present epidemic raged most
intensely in Europe in May, June,
and July. Moreover, in the case
of ordinary colds, the general
aymptoms (fever, pain, depres
sion) are by no means as severe ,oi
as sudden in their onset as they
are in influenza. Finally, ordinary
colds do not spread through the
community so rapidly or so ex
tensively as does influenza.
In most cases a person taken
sick with influenza feels siek rath
er suddenly. He feels weak, has
pains in the eyes, ears, head or
hack, and may be sore all over.
Many patients feel dizzy, some
■vomit. Most of the patients com
plain of feeling chilly, and with
thfs comes a fever in which the
temperature rises to 100 to 104.
In most eases the pulse remains
relatively low.
Tn appearance one is struck by
the fact that the patient looks
«ick. His eyes and the inner side
of his eyelids may be slightly
'"bloodshot," or "congested," as
the doctors says. There may be
running from the nose, or there
mav be some cough. These signs
of a cold may not be marked
nevertheless the patient looks and
feels very sick. Bacteriologists who have studied
influenza epidemics in the past,
have found in many of the cases
a very small rod-shaped germ
called, after its discoverer, Pfeif
fer 's bacillus. In other cases of
apparently the same kind of dis
ease there were found pneumo
coei. the germs of lobar pneu
monia. Still others have been
caused by strcptococi, and by
other germs with long names.
No matter what particular kind
of germ causes the epidemic, it is
now believed that influenza is al
ways spread from person to per
son, the germs being carried wi A h
the air along with the very small
droplets of mucus, expelled by
coughing or sneezing, forcefu'
talking, and the like by one whr
already has the germs of the dis
ease. Thev mav also be carried
about in the air in the form of
dust coming from dried mucus,
from coughing and sneezing, or
from careless people who spit on
the floor and on the sidewalk. As
in most other catching diseases, a
person who has only a mild at
tack of the disease himself may
give a very severe attack to
others. This appears not
to be true of "Spanish influenza' 5
According to newspaper reports
the King of Spain suffered an at
tack of influenza during the epi
demic thirty years ago, and was
again stricken during the recent
outbreak in Spain.
How can one guard
against influenza?
In guarding against disease of
all kinds, it. is important that the
body be 'kept strong and able to
fight off disease germs. This can
be done bv having a proper pro
portion of work, play, and rest,
by keeping the bodv well clothed,
and by eating sufficient, whole
some, and properly selected food.
Tn connection with diet, it is we\l
to remember that milk is one of
the best all-around foods obtain
able for adplts as well as chil
dren. So far as a disease like in
fluenza is concerne dhealth au
thorities everywhere recognize
the very close relation between
its spread and overcrowded
homes. While it. is not always
possible, especially in times like
the present, to avoid such over
crowding. people should consider
the health danger and make ev
ery effort to reduce the home
overcrowding to a minimum. The
value of fresh' air through open
windows can lot be over e-mpha
«îrM.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85034235/1918-10-10/ed-1/?sp=1&q=spanish+influenza</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86079080/1918-10-19/ed-1/?sp=4&q=spanish+influenza</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>SPANISH INFLUENZA.
Everyone seems to think he will
gave INFLUENZA.
Everyone wants to know how it
'egins.
It is really not probable that every
ne will be attacked by the disease
md it is not possible to give much
information as to how it begins or
ow to keep away from it.
Usually it starts just as a bad cold
toes. General ACHING, HEAD
ACHE, BACKACHE, often a chill
There is fever in some cases, fre
ilently the temperature runs high.
A great many cases of INFLUENZA
how no further symptoms than
hose of an ordinary cold. Some
imes the "ACHE" is worse than in
t cold.
Anyone who feels chilly, feverish,
'ACHY" should go home and go to
,ed. t
THE SUGGESTIONS MOST HELP
FUL ARE:
Don't worry about "catching"
mnything.
Keep your feet dry and warm and
jour head cool.
If you need a laxative, take it.
Don't over-eat.
Sleep nine hours. In a room by
rourself, if you can.
If you dsleep in a room with, others,
e a handkerehief over nos and
nouth.
Relieve the saeet ear by walkiag
Swork emvsif it is tree ualls.
Don't onugh or a MRS. ERNEST HOTARD DIES.
Mrs. Ernest Hotard, (nee Noemie
Millet) a native of this Parish but for
a number of years a resident of
McCall, La., died Thursday morning
after a brief attack of "Spanish In
fluenza.
Deceased was buried on Thursday
afternoon at Donaldsonville, La.,
Besides her husband and several
sons and daughters she olso leaves
several brothers and sisters to mourn
her sad and untimely demise.
Private John Horn, her youngest
son is at present in the United States
Army, stationed in Georgia.
Our condolences to the afflicted
ones.
J. DANIEL ORY IS INFLUENZA
VICTIM
The body of Private J. Daniel Ory,
a soldier who died in Pittsburg, arri
ved in St. John just in time to be
buried with his wife.
Mrs. Ory having died at Gramercy,
La., Thursday after an illness of
brief duration.
Private Ory was a native and life
long resident of this Pariqh.
Joint funeral services were held at
the St. Peter's Catholic Church, Reser
ve, La.
ASSISTANT ATTORNEY FOR
LOUISIANA DIES.
Vernon A. Coco, assistant attorney
general of Louisiana, died at the fa
mily hofe in New Orleans Friday
after an illness of seven days, which
began with influenza and culminated
in pneumonia.SPANISH INFLUENZA
Influenza is a "crowd disease."
KEEP OUT OF CROWDS.
Influenza spreads mostly by inhaling
"germs" when ignorant or careless
people cough or sneze without using
handkerchief. COVER UP EACH
COUGH AND SNEEZE.
Influenza spreads also by filthy
habit of spitting on floor or sidewalk
and public places. DO NOT SPIT
ON FLOOR OR SIDEWALK.
Influenza spreads also by use of
common drinking cups and common
towels in public places. AVOID
DRINKING IN PUBLIC PLACES.
DO NOT USE COMMON DRINK
ING CUP OR TOWEL.
If you feel sick and believe you
have "Spanish Influenza"
GO TO BED at once until the fever
stage is past;
Consult a doctor immediately;
See only the nurse and the doctor;
Take laxative as needed;
By resting give nature a chance;
The preventitive measures are al
most hwolly personal;
As the infection is transmitted
from one to another, those affected
be isolated in a room away from
other members of the family.
SPANISH INFLUENZA. IS VERY
MUCH LIKE OLD-FASHIONED
GRIP.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87065469/1918-10-10/ed-1/?sp=1&q=spanish+influenza</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>OXFORD IN IHE GRIP
OF SPANISH INFLUENZA
_
More than Two Hundred Cases
at t niveisity. Schools, Chur
ches. Theatres Are Closed.
Oxford, as well as all towns
■d cities in the United States.
is the throes of an epidemic of
ho Spanish influenza. The pub
sehools and churches as well
a the theatres have been closed
by the health officers. Many
cases are reported in the city,
nit no fatalities have l>een re
]K»i ted.
Out of more than 250 cases
developing at the University, not
a death has occured. This
-hows how well the disease is
beinpr handled there. Although
the college had not opened, more
than 400 students were on the
campus when the malady made
its appearance, and soon filled
the hospital. Then dormitories
were turned into hospitals,
where the students and soldiers
are lieiny treated by skilled
physicians and nursed by train
ed nurses.
The turn for the better was re
ported today, when more pati
ents were discharged than re
ceiver! at the hospitals.
i ons WHITE DEAD.
Mr. Walter Louis White, age
17 ears, son of Mr. and Mrs.
W. II. White, died al the home of
his father a few miles out of
town Tuesday eveiuiw at «»v#n
oclock.
The cause of his death was
pneumonia after Spanish In
fluenza. He was young and had
U»cn m Sheflield, Ala., for some
t me. While at that place he
contracted measles, which weak
ened him. and before he had re
gained his strength, the Spanish
influenza set in on him. pneu
monia following, which proved
fatal.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
